<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<program lastModified="2011-11-03 17:39:38">
	<tracks>
		<track name="Agile">
			<sessions>
				<session id="C011924BA93A1487C12578BF0063B39A" name="Influence and Authority: Using Your Personal Power to Get Things Done" startTime="2011-11-08T09:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="180">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>Have you ever felt as if you had the responsibility but not the authority? Or, that you needed something from someone, but you had to beg, borrow, or steal it? Maybe you’ve felt the joy of accomplishing something that you were responsible for, but had to work through someone else to accomplish.Almost no one has enough authority to finish the work we have responsibility for. And, we almost always have the ability to influence others, to use our personal power in the organization to become effective or make a difference.Some of us are are facile with our personal power. Others of us have concerns: am I manipulating people? am I manipulating the situation? am I being fair to others? Others of us are unsure where to start with using our influence.In this session, you will feel your personal power and experiment with how to use your influence.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="B6D0D391E1E2B1FEC1257864006A9A59" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="AFBC36B9CDD40950C12578D100305148" name="Visual planning and strategic" startTime="2011-11-08T13:30:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="180">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>Transform abstract ideas into visuals to promote critical thinking and spur creativity and innovation. We work collaboratively with session facilitators and participants to prioritizes ideas and build a vision of your future state. As the session comes to a close we help promote accountability by capturing next steps and action items. Afterward we work with you to create a visual transformation map, organizational chart, or gant chart of your future state vision.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="21AC75F874D6361AC12578D1002EAF4B" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="7D01121B0571C4C8C125789700678E5C" name="Domain-Driven Design and Agile" startTime="2011-11-10T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="Architecture" />
						<tag name="DDD" />
						<tag name="Domain-Driven Design" />
						<tag name="Java" />
						<tag name="lean" />
					</tags>
					<description>In this session, I will talk about how we have applied Domain-Driven Design in a project about 25000 man-hours size. I will talk about how DDD promotes a close customer relation, how we have worked with the domain and the domain model. I will also present patterns used in the project as well as some extensions to DDD as described in the book by Eric Evans. But mote of all, I will talk about how DDD works when it is applied systematically in a project over many years.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="A148467DF13F9792C1257885000B4E2A" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="F26D6E65ED277BF9C1257880005338A8" name="Beyond Method - Using Systems Thinking to Deepen Your Mastery of Agile" startTime="2011-11-10T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="Methodology" />
						<tag name="systems thinking" />
					</tags>
					<description>You've seen development methods come and go. If it seems like the methods were never good enough, that's because they weren’t. No recipe can be the right one always. But, we don't need to throw our methods away; we need to look beyond them, towards how we think. In this session, you will see how systems thinking tackles the counter-intuitive nature of many challenges. Your existing knowledge of how agile works will be complemented with an understanding of the principles on which it works.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="E3DE6B2E48E87028C125788000532C11" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="FEDA3487360C67B1C12578AB007D52F8" name="Tell Me Why - A 21st perspective on Agile" startTime="2011-11-10T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="Business Canvas Models" />
						<tag name="Complexity Theory" />
						<tag name="Design Thinking" />
						<tag name="Golden Circle" />
						<tag name="systems thinking" />
						<tag name="Simon Sinek" />
					</tags>
					<description>Simon Sinek created a TED talk about &quot;The Golden Circle&quot; that asks us to start with WHY we are doing something or creating something before we declare the WHAT. In between these are the HOW, creating 3 concentric circles. In this session, we will apply the Golden Circle to Agile adoption for 21st century innovative companies.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="7B7DD621EB77B08DC12578AB007D28BE" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="BBE7B5923164A101C1257864002195FC" name="Why common agile practice isn’t agile" startTime="2011-11-10T14:05:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="Methodology" />
						<tag name="UX" />
					</tags>
					<description>In 2001 the Agile Manifesto quietly described a set of values and principles that helped align a huge community of frustrated software practitioners. Finally we had an antidote to the dogmatic heavy processes we’d been forced to endure for the past couple decades. In this talk Jeff describes how much of today’s common agile practice has started to backslide towards the very thing we were avoiding 10 years ago. Jeff will describe how you can detect if you’re starting to backslide. You’ll hear some examples of real process innovation that to some appear to break agile rules but actually stays true to the spirit of agile development.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="0F5612DF26331F1AC12578640020C3F0" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="15C27180FBBF9833C12578CA0028BCA2" name="Making distributed teams work" startTime="2011-11-10T15:15:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="Business" />
						<tag name="collaboration" />
						<tag name="creativity" />
						<tag name="lean" />
						<tag name="Location" />
						<tag name="Methodology" />
						<tag name="pairing" />
						<tag name="presenting" />
						<tag name="speaking" />
						<tag name="team" />
						<tag name="Test" />
					</tags>
					<description>Developing software even with a collocated team is a complex endeavor. When the teams are distributed, especially over the geographical boundaries, it adds much more complexities to the whole production process. This session will closely discuss the challenges in such context and ways to make the distributed team development less hassleful and more effective to all the parties involved.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="B1553263EFB0373BC12578CA0027B62E" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="63F68835A37A407CC12578C5006A3870" name="How to select an agile vendor" startTime="2011-11-10T16:20:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="collaboration" />
					</tags>
					<description>When you are going to implement a new project, how are you going to determine when, if and how to buy from agile vendors? How do you determine if one supplier is better than another one? Choosing an agile vendor requires new strategies to procure agile vendors, new ways of thinking and other types of contracts. In this seminar, you will be guided through some principles and some alternatives will be presented.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="0940243B1CD9D40AC12578C5006981DA" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="52B390933572F214C125788000530552" name="Agile Portfolio Planning: Managing Your Project Portfolio" startTime="2011-11-11T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="Business" />
						<tag name="collaboration" />
						<tag name="lean" />
						<tag name="management" />
					</tags>
					<description>Whether you’ve been Agile for a while or still thinking about it, you have one thing in common with all other software teams. You have too much work to do. One of the valuable aspects of moving to an Agile approach for projects is the choices you have in managing the portfolio. You can use a kanban approach, a first-come-first-served queue, or one of several evaluation approaches to select which project to do next.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="B6D0D391E1E2B1FEC1257864006A9A59" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="EF7F4C9CE3544C5DC12578C4005B072C" name="Agile metrics – how to preserve and promote collaboration" startTime="2011-11-11T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="collaboration" />
					</tags>
					<description>Large organizations are using balanced scorecards and dashboards to measure, monitor and forecast the performance of the organization and connect those to its vision, goals and objectives. Metrics is important for management, but how do you design metrics for agile teams? How will the metrics affect the behavior of the teams? In this seminar, you will get an insight into different types of agile metrics that preserves and promotes collaboration of agile development teams.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="0940243B1CD9D40AC12578C5006981DA" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="6AEEB9CA6DB0F149C12578C4002A8F8E" name="Healthy Projects" startTime="2011-11-11T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>A healthy project requires clarity of project (what are we building), the customer (for whom are we building), the purpose (why are we building it), and of release schedules (when are we building it). But it doesn't stop there, a healthy project requires a collaborative contract and structure, an understanding of what quality means, constant communication between the team and all other stakeholders, and an appreciation of the project's trajectory. Agile and lean give us a highly configurable (and re-configurable) toolkit with which to build healthy projects. Jim Benson will discuss healthy projects with very different management structures and processes to illustrate that process is only healthy if it results in satisfied stakeholders.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="E8196EA0CF5974EFC1257864002027A7" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="99AD4E346149A5BBC1257928004197D1" name="Large scale agile – how to make it happen" startTime="2011-11-11T14:05:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="Methodology" />
					</tags>
					<description>Building the case for and transforming a large organization with huge legacy in product, process and culture in an agile direction is not for the faint-of-heart. However, if you are successful there is a promise for performance at a much higher level.
•	How to build the case for of the transformation
•	Why and what kind of pilots you should run
•	Preparing for the big leap and handling the consequences
•	What to deal with upfront and what to leave for later
•	Potential pitfalls to beware of</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="BFA7D277249CA4FDC125792800415AF7" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="88D2A6769CEB2944C12578C00074AB9F" name="Patterns of Effective Delivery" startTime="2011-11-11T15:15:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>Some teams are orders of magnitude more effective than others. Over the last year or so I've been working with, and observing, some very good teams with quite exceptional - and rather surprising - habits. In this talk Dan introduces the idea of delivery patterns - patterns of effective behaviour in delivery teams - and describes some of the more unusual but effective patterns he's been collecting.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="E032F082D5681850C12578C000742B1D" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
			</sessions>
		</track>
		<track name="Architecture">
			<sessions>
				<session id="34240B83E27CD5EFC12578C7004E4291" name="REST in Practice" startTime="2011-11-09T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Architecture" />
						<tag name="REST" />
					</tags>
					<description>In this talk we'll show how to implement business workflows and common patterns like event-driven computing. We'll see how many common-sense distributed systems principles and best practices are inverted as we design to increase surface area, scale, improve availability and compose services.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="5E26A118C9856B49C12578C7004C4C05" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="CC31CAAA9E5144D3C12578800042E29B" name="An architecture remake" startTime="2011-11-09T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Architecture" />
					</tags>
					<description>Statoil has recently done a large and complex architecture remake of a business critical application. The overall plan was to go from a situation with a codebase that was really hard, time consuming and riskful to make even small changes to and transform that into a situation with a codebase starting to get in control, and thereby making it smooth to make business driven improvements. In this presentation we’d like to share with you the story including what we learned and the key takeaways, both the happy parts and the tougher parts, both the technical aspects and the people things and more.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="99D83AB23621359EC12578800042A6CB" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="9934D5B29792B72FC12578C60011CA28" name="Test-Driven REST" startTime="2011-11-09T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Architecture" />
						<tag name="C#" />
						<tag name="REST" />
						<tag name="Test" />
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>REST's hypermedia constraint is all about getting things done - that is, making changes to the state of an application to achieve a particular goal. Put simply, in a web-based hypermedia system, clients apply HTTP's uniform interface to operate links and forms in pursuit of their application goals.

In this session I'll discuss the implementation of machine-to-machine interactions in a hypermedia-driven distributed system. I'll look at how we can develop and test discrete parts of a workflow, and build adaptable clients that can be guided on the fly to complete their application goals. I'll conclude by introducing you to a hands-on tutorial that you can complete using the new Microsoft Web APIs.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="Unknown" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="347E1D7C7E27EB04C12578C0006C8C82" name="Public + Private = Reality. Patterns for building solutions that span public and private clouds" startTime="2011-11-09T14:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Architecture" />
						<tag name="backend programming" />
						<tag name="Methodology" />
						<tag name="Windows Azure" />
					</tags>
					<description>Many organizations have scenarios where they would like to take advantage of the public cloud for their business but are unable to do so today. This can range from concerns related to government or industry compliance to legacy systems to data sovereignty concerns.This session reviews how to architect solutions that span private and public clouds, incorporating lessons learned from real world customer engagements.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="7E1C126299BC6BFFC12578B8006454D1" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="079A6B072E22DDDEC125788000535ABB" name="Architecture Without an End State" startTime="2011-11-09T15:40:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>Most architecture efforts have a strong waterfall nature to them. Architects create an end-state vision with a multi-year plan to achieve it. Of course, the business and technological contexts both change long before that can be achieved. The result is a series of half-finished, very expensive, enterprise architecture initiatives. Instead, we should create architecture that is specifically optimized for change, with principles about where to place certain decisions and how to adapt over time.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="5252E2BD2AAE735BC125786400213B84" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="18997511624446AFC12578C10070C3BD" name="Small Stories Tall Tales from the Road to Big Data" startTime="2011-11-09T16:45:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Architecture" />
						<tag name="big data" />
						<tag name="Business" />
						<tag name="Cloud Computing" />
						<tag name="databases" />
						<tag name="lean" />
						<tag name="Methodology" />
						<tag name="nosql" />
						<tag name="usage" />
					</tags>
					<description>A personal look at the people, projects trends behind the NOSQL movement. Drawn from my experience travelling the world to record The NOSQL Tapes (http://nosqltapes.com/).</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="8CD19806A35933E4C12578B0005DF785" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="1EEC3564EEB46BDAC125782300501E1E" name="How to not apply CQRS" startTime="2011-11-10T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>This talk will define first what CQRS actually is. After we will look
at common misapplications of CQRS and how to avoid them.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="53988259A9936183C125787F006B2920" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="D0044AC99314A86BC125782300501E23" name="Event Sourcing explained" startTime="2011-11-10T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Architecture" />
						<tag name="Java" />
					</tags>
					<description>Your business wants to use data from your application, but in a way that you didn't anticipate from the beginning. Now what do you do? If you are using EventSourcing, you're in luck, and this session will describe how this technique can help you deal with these types of situations, and more.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="528D0D5817167F81C12578AE001F8E32" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="C178C46D3B53B7A0C125787F00697A9D" name="Who needs a service bus anyway?" startTime="2011-11-10T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>Although Enterprise Service Buses have been used in many larger companies, small and medium enterprises have often been put off by the high cost of these large middleware packages. These days we're seeing more open-source service buses gaining popularity and many developers are beginning to get curious - what would I use it for? Join Udi to get the scoop as well as see some patterns in action with NServiceBus.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="647275791EA01DF3C125787F0069598A" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="3BD20107E57DC8C2C125782300501FF7" name="Rest from use-cases" startTime="2011-11-10T14:05:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Architecture" />
						<tag name="Java" />
					</tags>
					<description>Building REST API's for distributed applications is becoming more and more popular. But, there is one thing that most developers miss, which is the HATEOAS requirement, i.e. linking. This session will explain how exposing use-cases brings a natural solution to this problem, and how this will simplify both API development, documentation, as well as client development.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="528D0D5817167F81C12578AE001F8E32" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="79EF4636635ADF03C12578C0006BF9EC" name="&quot;Cloud First&quot; Architecture" startTime="2011-11-10T15:15:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Architecture" />
						<tag name="backend programming" />
						<tag name="Methodology" />
						<tag name="systems thinking" />
						<tag name="Windows Azure" />
					</tags>
					<description>Modern applications should be designed with a “Cloud First” mentality. Rather than just “move stuff” to the cloud, architects should be designing software that is autonomous, asynchronous, stateless, and based on standards. Whether public, private or hybrid clouds, taking this approach will pay dividends now and in the future. This session discusses the subject in depth and looks at the architectural patterns and approaches using real world solutions.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="7E1C126299BC6BFFC12578B8006454D1" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="00E2DD60AA4CD15AC12578BF0063923C" name="Old school architecture" startTime="2011-11-10T16:20:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="API" />
						<tag name="Architecture" />
					</tags>
					<description>Every year, we seem to get smarter and more adventurous with our architectures for this crazy changing world that has seen client-server, n-tier, SOA, Big Data, REST and lots more. While each expedition is filled with the thrill of adventure, I often see teams creating old messes in new territory with cool new toys. In this talk I will highlight some fail points and revert to old school ideas to use them in these new adventures. Hopefully, we will make smaller messes, myself included.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="A4EAE7D647C659F0C12578BF006374CE" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
			</sessions>
		</track>
		<track name="Collaboration">
			<sessions>
				<session id="D74B2C7CF6371338C12578AB007D4298" name="Collaborative Visioning Learning in the Agile Organization" startTime="2011-11-09T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="A3" />
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="collaboration" />
						<tag name="Empathy Maps" />
						<tag name="Kanban Board" />
						<tag name="Mother Strategies" />
						<tag name="ORID" />
						<tag name="Pascal Dennis" />
						<tag name="True North" />
						<tag name="Value Stream Map" />
					</tags>
					<description>21st century innovative companies do not rely on a top-down or command-and-control approach for how they create vision and deliver against that vision. In this session, Jean Tabaka gives you straight forward examples of how organizations apply collaboration as a business advantage. Her approach show how the collective wisdom from the entire organization creates better vision and better consensus on how to deliver against the vision.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="7B7DD621EB77B08DC12578AB007D28BE" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="6AFB6F927328A8DDC12578800052D01C" name="Collaboration by better understanding yourself" startTime="2011-11-09T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>Prepare to reflect deeply into yourself and inspect what in-built responses we all have as people. Identifying these behaviours helps us understand their impact on our ability to collaborate with other people, for better or for worse. Only by truly understanding yourself will you really improve how you interact and collaborate with others</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="770A27AE50FC60D7C1257880001E855E" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="5C9C243AA9D1083EC12578D100304301" name="Visual Collaboration" startTime="2011-11-09T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>Scribble, doodle, draw and be a more effective communicator. Visuals are powerful tool for communication. In this session co-founders of ImageThink will show you how visuals are helping people in all industries see the big picture.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="21AC75F874D6361AC12578D1002EAF4B" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="20FA1148AFC3C904C12578800052DE87" name="Pairing is fun!" startTime="2011-11-09T14:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="collaboration" />
						<tag name="Dev excellence" />
						<tag name="Dev.Excellence" />
						<tag name="pair programming" />
						<tag name="pairing" />
					</tags>
					<description>What is pairing all about? Is it only about writing code or tests, or is it more than that? Come have some fun and learn how to pair without writing code. You might even find yourself laughing and making friends.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="F0EDAADBD99BBC4AC1257880001E2AAB" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="B4BF8553C0A21CF1C12578800054CFE2" name="Managing For Collaboration" startTime="2011-11-09T15:40:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="collaboration" />
						<tag name="management" />
						<tag name="systems thinking" />
					</tags>
					<description>Managers create a system, an environment, in which the teams can thrive or dive. But which one? And, how do they do it?Agile managers create an environment of collaboration for the teams and for the managers. They do this by optimizing at the highest level of their influence, not the lowest. This is a huge change and challenge, because it’s opposite from how they have worked and been asked to work in the past. We’ll discuss the four prongs of management: to set the strategy, to build trusting relationships, to remove organizational obstacles, and to build the capacity of the organization.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="B6D0D391E1E2B1FEC1257864006A9A59" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="D15DD5694FF3D4C4C12578B7001B7696" name="The Power of Play - Making Good Teams Great" startTime="2011-11-09T16:45:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="collaboration" />
						<tag name="creativity" />
						<tag name="Games" />
					</tags>
					<description>“Screw work let’s play!” Do you sometimes wish you could goof off work and play? In this interactive presentation, inspired by the theory and experience of play, we’ll demonstrate why play isn’t just essential for creativity and innovation, but crucial to our survival and overall well-being. We’ll begin with the definition of play based on a 6-step framework followed by an exploration of why we play and how we play. We’ll investigate the relationship of work and play and demonstrate how, instead of being mutually exclusive, both are necessary for personal and group creativity and achievement. We’ll finish off with 7 guidelines for bringing more play into your life. And if you play your cards right, you’ll leave with plenty of ideas to achieve your recommended daily amount of play!</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="BBE4591C8578285BC12578B50077706E" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
			</sessions>
		</track>
		<track name="Cool Languages">
			<sessions>
				<session id="B237AEB017136A2BC12578800041722B" name="Have you tried Mirah yet?" startTime="2011-11-11T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Java" />
						<tag name="Other Languages" />
					</tags>
					<description>Mirah is a pragmatic approach to JVM languages. These days, we have dynamic languages offering higher productivity and fancy web frameworks, functional languages promising to save us from concurrency headaches, and static-typed languages giving us almost infinitely extensible type systems. Mirah is different, delivering a rich set of language features with no runtime dependencies. It borrows Ruby's syntax for clean code, but it is static-typed with optional dynamic typing like C#. It supports macro expansions like C, making it more fluid and extensible. The type system is almost identical to Java, and the compiler can output both class files and Java source files. Come see why Mirah may be your next JVM language.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="DF6984CDE5A1FE17C1257880003E9631" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="8F9EF3BBD7B2B5F6C125793B0080E90D" name="The top ten things in Clojure that will make you a better developer in any language" startTime="2011-11-11T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Clojure" />
					</tags>
					<description>Clojure is an exciting new functional programming language with a fresh approach to reducing the complexity of writing software for today's multi-core reality. 

Claiming that mutable state is the new spaghetti code, it radically simplifies concurrent programming by defaulting to immutability. This allows the programmer to safely share data between threads without getting into concurrency issues.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="E86251FB36CCC6FDC125793B0080A562" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="EA07A209A5DD68A2C1257926003DF102" name="Graphical System Design with G" startTime="2011-11-11T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="windows8" />
						<tag name="RTOS" />
						<tag name="FPGA" />
						<tag name="BIG picture" />
						<tag name="creativity" />
						<tag name="Design Thinking" />
						<tag name="humanistic" />
						<tag name="Other Languages" />
						<tag name="software craftsmanship" />
						<tag name="Visualization" />
					</tags>
					<description>The first vision for G was to do for measurement systems what excel did for accounting. Now the vision is to be the google earth of your development project, letting you go from high level system views down do fine details in FPGA signals. Do you ever create systems abridging the realms of Desktop|Embedded|FPGA ? Picture this: a graphical programing language diagram suitable for designing such a system. You may have written your last line of code. By the way, how else were you going to use that shiny new tablet?</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="Unknown" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="93F7F45D4C4E3719C12578CE0042E67D" name="Haskell" startTime="2011-11-11T14:05:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>Haskell is now quite widely used, but its most important contributions are the ideas that it embodies. In this talk I will focus on one of these ideas, namely type classes, with a few anecdotes and reflections along the way about the process of developing the language.
 
Type classes are probably Haskell's most distinctive feature. The original idea is very neat and, better still, it led to a long series of subsequent generalisations and innovations. Indeed, although the language is now nineteen years old, Haskell's type system is still in a state of furious development. For example, I am involved in adding type-level functions to Haskell, as I will briefly describe.
 
I will explain what type classes are, how they differ from the classes of mainstream object oriented languages, why I think they are so cool, and what the hot topics are. I'll give plenty of examples, so you don't need to already know Haskell.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="2953F952AD4E36A5C12578570058BC9B" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="B626B935DB1BEA4BC12578CC00261886" name="Modeling concurrency in Ruby and beyond" startTime="2011-11-11T15:15:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Architecture" />
						<tag name="backend programming" />
						<tag name="concurrency" />
						<tag name="Hackers" />
						<tag name="ruby" />
						<tag name="systems thinking" />
					</tags>
					<description>The world of concurrent computation is a complicated one. We have to think about the hardware, the runtime, and even choose between half a dozen different models and primitives: fork/wait, threads, shared memory, message passing, semaphores, and transactions just to name a few. And that's only the beginning.What about &quot;alternative concurrency models&quot;? Can you name any, how are they different, what do they give us? Stop by to learn about CSP, Actor, and other models, in Ruby and beyond.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="482EA8E9642F26E7C12578CC0023E5B5" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
			</sessions>
		</track>
		<track name="Entrepreneurship">
			<sessions>
				<session id="A756DCA24DC3DFABC12579230054C430" name="How a Dutch rapper ends up in Swedish startup - lessons learned" startTime="2011-11-10T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="entrepreneurship" />
					</tags>
					<description>Drawing upon his background in media and entertainment management, first as a rapper and a with a background in TV production, Frank will be sharing insights from his experiences as a serial entrepreneur. Co-founding several award winning start-ups including IRL, Verbeterdebuurt, and now his current career passion, taking Swedish based, Qubulus international. A session sure to be filled with real life example of lessons learned as well as vibrant and inspiring.

</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="A67B9A0BDBE63DC1C12579230050D36F" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="32B7CDFEEF94841EC125792D0051F365" name="What stirreth a VC's Heart" startTime="2011-11-10T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="entrepreneurship" />
					</tags>
					<description>If you have a great idea, one that commands your attention and eclipses
all else, but misses that one slippery element- backing- you want to
arrive early to this session. Christian, who has taken in the view (and
from that, developed a few of his own) from every angle of
entrepreneurship, will be touching upon the 4 essentials for the ambitious
and committed entrepreneur:

What a VC looks for, and especially Sunstone capital in this case
Layout of the processes around financing, including selection
The Do's and Don'ts when approaching a VC
Lessons learned from the VC viewpoint</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="D423BAB549E212FAC125792D00511324" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="4F5B9966D4CE7E25C125790800590063" name="Going For It: From Side Project to Startup - Building a Company One Evening at a Time" startTime="2011-11-10T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Augmented Reality" />
						<tag name="Core Location" />
						<tag name="entrepreneurship" />
						<tag name="Geo-fencing" />
						<tag name="Geo-location" />
						<tag name="history" />
						<tag name="Location" />
						<tag name="Privacy" />
						<tag name="software craftsmanship" />
						<tag name="startups" />
						<tag name="Smart phone" />
						<tag name="Visualization" />
					</tags>
					<description>Location-based platform Geoloqi was born out of a year of bootstrapping while co-founders Aaron Parecki and Amber Case worked full-time. This session will tell the story of Geoloqi's transition from side project to startup, highlighting the technology, decisions, difficulties, triumphs and struggles along the way.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="1D58C1B897A2B6ACC12579080054F93D" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="C1E460297250AC2AC12579250078C8FC" name="From Småland's woods to silicon valley. A modern Wilhelm Moberg story" startTime="2011-11-10T14:05:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="entrepreneurship" />
					</tags>
					<description>A company is like a baby. And it takes as long to allow it to grow. Don't fool yourself and be prepared for a journey from Påskallavik to Menlo Park. It takes a village to raise a child, and a community to grow a company.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="4200BFDFA1686EECC12579250078A115" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="3DC0C343A9D124DBC1257925007854DF" name="Start(ing)up! Opportunities, Threats and Support (in Sweden)" startTime="2011-11-10T15:15:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="entrepreneurship" />
					</tags>
					<description>An inspirational journey on how to build sustainable business and help it grow. Also discussed will be support the entrepreneur can expect to receive when wanting to realize his/her idea of a start-up in Sweden.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="0CF3F2D2060EF4BFC12579250040A854" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="7D9A051ECB55B731C12579250042CA34" name="Launching your product or startup: a framework" startTime="2011-11-10T16:20:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="entrepreneurship" />
						<tag name="iOS" />
						<tag name="iPhone" />
						<tag name="Kanban Board" />
						<tag name="startups" />
					</tags>
					<description>Launch. The process is vital to any product or startup's success, but it's difficult to get information from founders who've lived through it. Get answers to your questions, from the co-founder of a funded startup that recently had to answer all these questions: When should you launch? Should you launch a &quot;lean MVP&quot;, or &quot;wait till it’s perfect&quot;? No generalized advice here - this talk will address common startup/product archetypes and help you apply direct learning to your product and your team.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="A864AFF977F4015BC1257925004A2841" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
			</sessions>
		</track>
		<track name="Excellence">
			<sessions>
				<session id="ACDC277AEE1C1B75C12578CE0024556D" name="Get Excellent using Git" startTime="2011-11-08T09:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="360">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Architecture" />
						<tag name="git" />
						<tag name="pairing" />
						<tag name="versioncontrol" />
					</tags>
					<description>This workshop will take very new and emerging Git users and bring them to a heightened level of productivity by leveraging Git's powerful range of productivity features in a hands on exploration of much of what Git has to offer. Some topics to be covered include:

* Rebasing
* Merging
* Branching models
* Working with refs
* Git internals
* The Reflog
* Reset, revert and the right way to undo
* Building your own Git scripts</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="Unknown" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="DCE5F40FDBB79511C12578AD0072BA42" name="Visualisations and Infographics: How to gain users and influence people" startTime="2011-11-09T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="big data" />
						<tag name="Data" />
						<tag name="Data Scientist" />
						<tag name="Infographics" />
						<tag name="Privacy" />
						<tag name="Visualization" />
					</tags>
					<description>This class will talk about the value of good visualisations for conveying information and getting your story across. Whether that's a location privacy scandal that caused US Senate hearings, or something more day-to-day, when you're dealing with messy data presenting it in the right manner can mean the difference between fame and obscurity. A successful application, or an ignominious failure.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="0CE18D33C0D2E936C12578C3005BC6F5" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="F9AC2F963821F1A1C12578BD006527A8" name="Hacking Developer Productivity" startTime="2011-11-09T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Dev excellence" />
					</tags>
					<description>Serious software development requires the proper use of tools, practices, and settings to eliminate the tedium involved with creating quality software. From the individual developer to a large distributed team, there are many tips, tricks, and shortcuts that can save seconds, minutes, or even hours every day. By using the proper tools, following the best practices, and optimizing the development environment, this talk will help you get things done more quickly and with more predictable results.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="CE4242DCD64AB619C12578BD003879C5" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="C6DAA6CB6B99350CC12578800053784C" name="When the Fur Flies: Dev and Ops Collaboration at the Worst of Times" startTime="2011-11-09T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>This talk addresses the need for developers to understand and collaborate with operations, as well as the consequences when collaboration does not happen. It's an argument for DevOps, by examining a pair of case studies: one where this collaboration happened, and one where it did not.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="5252E2BD2AAE735BC125786400213B84" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="A759BF2B194583BDC12578B7006B6B17" name="A less technical talk on technical communication" startTime="2011-11-09T14:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Dev excellence" />
					</tags>
					<description>As developers, we spend more time communicating with humans than we do with computers. How can we do that more effectively? How can we be more accurate and concise in our communication? How can we best find analogies which illustrate the desired point? When working with difficult to describe concepts, how can we more easily define them and improve our communication of them? What short and long term benefits can we reap from learning to more effectively communicate? (Yeah, very touchy-feely...)</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="9428A6E3C0EADE3BC12578B7006B4D2F" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="C5E4CC16CBD5D7B7C125786300787484" name="What Testers and Developers Can Learn From Each Other" startTime="2011-11-09T15:40:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="Test" />
					</tags>
					<description>The rise of cross-functional agile teams has helped to bring a greater sense of collaboration and mutual respect between developers and testers. But many teams still struggle with the basic issues. What is the role of the tester in an agile team? How many testers do we need? What does a team gain from having professional testers? Perhaps there is another way to approach these questions.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="D379E52E40B16BF3C125786300774F86" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="0F8D35B4C3E5C416C12578B8002724A6" name="API - the hidden UI" startTime="2011-11-09T16:45:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Dev excellence" />
					</tags>
					<description>Just as the food chain is made out of more actors than the bacteria and the top predator, the software chain contains more than the CPU and the end user. User experience is typically about the end user experience, but we should not forget the developers. This talk will explore the API as a user interface; what makes it more or less user friendly? What difference do things like naming, namespace structure and constructor design make? What if you could make other developers really reuse your code?</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="A75255F52203D121C12578B8002716D3" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="CA9F1343F66179EFC125792F002F470F" name="Keeping up with the changing landscape of software usage. (Are you prepared for where the market is going?)" startTime="2011-11-10T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Dev excellence" />
						<tag name="Dev.Excellence" />
					</tags>
					<description>The way software is being consumed is changing dramatically. In this session we will talk about how Hardware and Software has changed and what we need to consider to make the best of the devices available. How consumers are using and accessing data from multiple locations and the challenges that brings to us as software developers; and looking into the future, we will touch on how as developers WE NEED technologies to exploit the power of not only the CPU, but also the under used GPU to safe guard our development time investment into the future.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="A9818555573FB9FEC125792F002F1A12" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="EA7B5288E1D25F95C12578BE00550AF6" name="Programming and minimalism: Lessons from Orwell The Clash" startTime="2011-11-10T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>Programming is writing. A programmer's job is to express abstract ideas in a specific language - just like the poet, the essayist, and the composer. But while writers and composers spend years improving their style, many programmers think style stops with &quot;two-space indentation&quot;. This needs to change. This presentation will discuss style in music, writing, and software. We'll look at such diverse sources as George Orwell, Mozart, and punk music, and will find that much of art revolves around complexity and minimalism - just like software. Finally, we'll look at specific patterns and tools for writing software that is not just effective and efficient, but stylistically beautiful.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="76A43012DA9334E1C12578B9005E7936" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="B15735A6E97B2DD0C12578C90067481F" name="Fast Ruby on Rails Tests" startTime="2011-11-10T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Ruby on Rails" />
					</tags>
					<description>Look at your Rails unit test suite. Now look at mine(http://screencast.com/t/O2LhGoVSG). Now look at yours again.Mine are sub-second. Yours aren't.Having a slow unit test suite can hinder an effective test-first ortest-driven approach to development. As you add tests, the suitestarts to slow down to the point where you stop running them aftereach change. Some people even talk about multi-minute unit testssuites! Band-aids like spork are just covering up the problem.Test-driven development is a major player in keeping your designmalleable and accepting of new features, but when you stop payingattention to the messages your tests are sending you, you lose thisbenefit.In this talk, I will go over some techniques for keeping your testsuite lean and fast. Along the way, we'll discuss the designimprovements that come out of these changes.Now, look at my unit test suite again(http://screencast.com/t/O2LhGoVSG). Yours can be like mine.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="33A9B170937DDE76C12578C900660087" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="06D583C0CA2F3B9FC125787F006A2A4C" name="Zen and the Art of Software" startTime="2011-11-10T14:05:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Dev excellence" />
					</tags>
					<description>Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance is a book about Quality; what it is, where it exists, and how we may try to attain it. In this talk, I will use passages from the book to introduce ideas on how we, as software developers, might try to improve the Quality both of the software we create and of ourselves. I’ll talk about what “Quality” means in the context of software, how to measure it, and the importance of close interaction with users at all stages of application development.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="D26D0355769B55A0C125787F006A0895" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="83ECBC8E854860C3C125792D004CE451" name="Ways to make your app more successful with social networks" startTime="2011-11-10T15:15:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Facebook" />
						<tag name="HTML5" />
					</tags>
					<description>Come learn best practices on how to build an app that gives your users a great social experience. Learn how to use Facebook's social channels and plugins to promote your application without spamming your users. Come see how you can use tools in the Facebook platform such as Insights, Ads, and Timeline to better understand your users and foster mutually beneficial communication. You will leave this session with a broad understanding of the many component that you can use to make your app great.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="462C3A45DFB543EDC125792D004CAD7A" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="83AE94EF6B90C3D7C125787F006B3C58" name="How to get productive in a project in 24h" startTime="2011-11-10T16:20:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>So you are entering a new contract, or maybe its just a new project you are being transfered to. How do you get up, going, and committing on your first day? How to identify the areas of the system that are risky or problematic? This session looks at tools and strategies to reach this goal coming from a speaker who regularly works for less than a week with a team and needs to provide value within that period of time.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="53988259A9936183C125787F006B2920" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="EF0E824433F77F2DC12578B60036A030" name="Software development in F1: challenges, complexity and struggle for excellence" startTime="2011-11-11T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="Dev excellence" />
						<tag name="Dev.Excellence" />
						<tag name="lean" />
						<tag name="Methodology" />
					</tags>
					<description>This experience report is based on more than 3 years of software development in F1 with Scrum, Lean and XP, developing evolving and maintaining software to support the F1 racing team from the vehicle conception and throughout every test and race.Have we survived the challenge? How did we survived? Which team and coding practices emerged? What are the most valuable lessons learned from this experience?</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="D8F29D3222E036ECC12578B600368BB9" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="4D92D462935B229BC12579210042420B" name="Domain Models and Composite Applications" startTime="2011-11-11T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Architecture" />
					</tags>
					<description>As developers use DDD principles to build larger and richer systems, many of them run into performance and maintainability problems as their domain model grows to meet the demands of the system. Performance problems addressed by eager fetching reappear later in other parts of the system, now requiring the use of lazy loading for the same entities. Join Udi as he shows the use of Bounded Contexts to turn monolithic systems into composite applications, now with multiple lean and mean domain models</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="647275791EA01DF3C125787F0069598A" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="005830DD600709C9C125792D0058AF14" name="Credit Crunch Code – Time to Pay Back the Technical Debt" startTime="2011-11-11T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>Technical debt is the cost of putting off good development practices. This debt, must be paid back to avoid the “interest payments” becoming crippling. This presentation will further define technical debt, before examining some anti-patterns and how to avoid them. We’ll then look at how to put a financial cost on technical debt, and end by examining some measures to identify technical debt in a code base.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="7D13AA6B3FB4DE0EC12578BD0033B1DC" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="FB48CD0812D49B7CC125788000549763" name="Development is a game!" startTime="2011-11-11T14:05:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Dev excellence" />
						<tag name="Dev.Excellence" />
						<tag name="game-ification" />
						<tag name="Games" />
						<tag name="social activism" />
					</tags>
					<description>Certifications are a mixed bag. Training is sometimes great, sometimes inadequate. How do these things affect you in your career development? In this session we talk about exciting ways to change this - to make learning fun and relevant, to make certifications have meaning, and to create a powerful community.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="F0EDAADBD99BBC4AC1257880001E2AAB" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="0573B9677845BC25C12578B70068A0B7" name="My boss doesn't understand me" startTime="2011-11-11T15:15:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>Well, you probably don't understand your boss either. You both have different value needs - your jobs and career paths are different, your performance metrics are different, the political games you play are different. What's needed is a value translator. Visual controls like kanban can serve as a visual translator ... while they help you and your team manage your project. Jim Benson will describe how value translators work how to gain an appreciation for other people's value needs, and how to normalize those needs for better team performance and a happier workplace.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="E8196EA0CF5974EFC1257864002027A7" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
			</sessions>
		</track>
		<track name="Java">
			<sessions>
				<session id="127EB2AECE981049C12578C4004EEC41" name="Fast Track to Scala" startTime="2011-11-07T09:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="720">
					<tags>
						<tag name="jvm" />
						<tag name="Scala" />
					</tags>
					<description>This two-day course, designed by Martin Odersky, the creator of the Scala programming language, and Heiko Seeberger, a recognized Scala expert, will give you an excellent grounding in Scala.It is intended to enable developers or development managers, who are experienced programmers in Java or other production languages like C++, C# or Ruby, to confidently start programming in Scala. No previous knowledge of Scala is assumed.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="7064422D70BBE62EC12578C4004E92DB" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="E838C9253DE919F4C12578CE0024B15B" name="Monitoring Critical Code Quality Metrics with Sonar" startTime="2011-11-09T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="continuousdelivery" />
						<tag name="continuousintegration" />
						<tag name="metrics" />
					</tags>
					<description>Sonar is an open source tool that brings together the best of breed static and dynamic analysis of Java projects. The result is a unified view of problematic areas of your code on a time-line basis, allowing the team to attack the problems with the best ROI, and maintain a more watchful eye for positive and risky trends in the codebase in the future.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="542D5DF563711C81C12578CE0023CB5C" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="68C70475E884E6BBC12578C000346117" name="Not quite object oriented" startTime="2011-11-09T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Architecture" />
						<tag name="Clojure" />
						<tag name="functional" />
						<tag name="Java" />
						<tag name="object orientation" />
						<tag name="Other Languages" />
						<tag name="Scala" />
					</tags>
					<description>The JVM seems to have a fresh breeze blowing throw it with alternative languages like Groovy and Ruby. But for me, the standouts are Scala and Clojure. Many of us grew up with OO and Java was our language of expression. But Scala and Clojure are different. They have a functional side and expressing OO thoughts functionally is painful. We we will explore what it takes to shift your thinking gradually (not overnight) to take advantage of Scala and Clojure's functional side.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="A4EAE7D647C659F0C12578BF006374CE" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="B432D0837FCB3038C12578AE0020465C" name="Java EE 6 end-to-end app development" startTime="2011-11-09T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="GlassFish" />
						<tag name="Java" />
						<tag name="JavaEE6" />
						<tag name="NetBeans" />
					</tags>
					<description>This slide-free session will explain the simplicity and power of the Java EE 6 platform. The session will start with NetBeans IDE as the presentation tool and build an end-to-end application using JSF 2, JPA, CDI, EJB, Servlets, and other similar technologies.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="99B910563CAB529BC12578AE002033A4" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="74890E7A7C1C8F2DC12578CB0004272B" name="Apache Buildr: Build Like You Code!" startTime="2011-11-09T14:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="ant" />
						<tag name="build system" />
						<tag name="ivy" />
						<tag name="Java" />
						<tag name="maven" />
						<tag name="Other Languages" />
						<tag name="Ruby on Rails" />
						<tag name="Scala" />
					</tags>
					<description>Buildr is a modern build system for Java-based applications including support for Scala, Groovy and a growing number of JVM languages and tools. Buildr combines the expressiveness of the Ruby scripting language with a familiar dependency-based task execution model and project-level structure similar to Apache Maven. This session will introduce Buildr and demonstrate practical solutions to common build problems.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="F645E05E18923A44C12578CB0002AF1D" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="FEC24BA2C65B9EC8C12578C4004EC61A" name="Scala in Action" startTime="2011-11-09T15:40:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="jvm" />
						<tag name="Scala" />
					</tags>
					<description>You don't yet speak Scala? Then let us invite you to a journey on which we will explore the outstanding features of this programming language for the Java Virtual Machine.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="7064422D70BBE62EC12578C4004E92DB" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="4CE0923773584417C12578AE00207DCC" name="Deploying your Java EE 6 applications using GlassFish 3.1" startTime="2011-11-09T16:45:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Architecture" />
						<tag name="GlassFish" />
						<tag name="Java" />
						<tag name="JavaEE6" />
					</tags>
					<description>Java EE 6 provides new capabilities to develop and deploy enterprise and Web applications with a simplified developer experience. GlassFish 3.1 has several features that are typically required for deploying a Java EE 6 application in production. Clustering, High Availability, Centralized Administration, OSGi/JavaEE Apps, RESTful administration, and many other features make the overall experience very pleasing. This session will provide details about the features and show live demos.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="99B910563CAB529BC12578AE002033A4" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="FD8C947547CFA3C1C12578F8004D7935" name="Data Access 2.0? Please welcome - Spring Data!" startTime="2011-11-11T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>Oliver Gierke is engineer at SpringSource, a division of VMware, project lead of the Spring Data JPA module and involved into other Spring Data modules (e.g. MongoDB) as well. He has been into developing enterprise applications and open source projects for over 6 years now. His working focus is centered around software architecture, Spring and persistence technologies. He is regularly speaking at German and international conferences as well as author of technology articles.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="CC0D20783930E1DEC12578F8004D5FEB" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="05775C4ACB671289C12579170032284D" name="Java 7 What's New, What's Next?" startTime="2011-11-11T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Java" />
					</tags>
					<description>Finally Java SE 7 is GA and you can start using it. This talk will cover the most important new features of the language and the virtual machine. It will also cover some features that did not make it in to the SE 7 release. Finally we will discuss current state of Java as an ecosystem and my analysis and hopes for the future.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="0C260088D8D00CB2C12579170027B27F" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="F7E761DB80D44D1FC12578AF0023836E" name="What the JVM Does With your Bytecode when Nobody's Looking" startTime="2011-11-11T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Java" />
					</tags>
					<description>Look at you, hacker. You think you know all there is about building apps for the JVM. You've used all the cool tools. You've written your own persistence library or web frameworks. Maybe you've even implemented a JVM language. But do you really know what happens to your code after you hand it off to the JVM? This talk will explore the guts of the OpenJDK VM, Hotspot. We'll take a few simple examples from bytecode through optimization and compilation all the way down to assembly code, and explore how you can ensure your code runs as fast as possible. We'll see how generational garbage collection works with the aid of VisualVM and learn a few JVM flags to help you tune it. We'll play with invokedynamic and show how it fits into the JVM story. And we'll chat about how you can take advantage of this newfound knowledge to be a better JVM user.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="DF6984CDE5A1FE17C1257880003E9631" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="AF7E65533E23A394C12578C60071F2DE" name="Get Dressed for Success - From Swing to JavaFX" startTime="2011-11-11T14:05:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Java" />
						<tag name="JavaFX" />
						<tag name="Swing" />
						<tag name="UI" />
						<tag name="UX" />
					</tags>
					<description>Swing has been a great retainer for years, but with todayís focus on rich user interfaces, many Java applications can benefit from using JavaFX instead. The question is, how do you manage that when youíre stuck with a an old Swing front end? This presentation starts with a typical Swing application and replaces parts of it with a shiny new JavaFX interface. During this transformation event listeners are replaced by JavaFX bindings, hardcoded color constants are replaced by style sheets and instead of the limited HTML support in Swing, the JavaFX WebView component is used to display formatted content. After this presentation the audience will have a thorough understanding of how JavaFX can replace all or parts of a Swing user interface.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="E0DADC8949FC97DFC12578C400266558" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="925D1D460A346263C12578AE0020BFAE" name="Vaadin, Rich Web Apps in Server-Side Java without Plug-ins or JavaScript" startTime="2011-11-11T15:15:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Architecture" />
						<tag name="Java" />
						<tag name="UI" />
						<tag name="Web Dev" />
					</tags>
					<description>Vaadin Framework provides a desktop-like programming model on the server for creating Rich Internet Applications (RIAs) in plain Java - without the need for HTML, XML, plug-ins or JavaScript. In this session, one of the core Vaadin developers lays out the key concepts of the server-side RIA development model and shows how to build an application with Vaadin ground up.
</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="77D0C918FC118601C12578AE0020ADB4" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
			</sessions>
		</track>
		<track name="Keynote">
			<sessions>
				<session id="A070A44D541C0188C1257904006CA90C" name="Only your mom wants to use your website" startTime="2011-11-09T08:30:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>If you're not developing for the end user, who the hell are you developing for? Whenever you launch a new product, you've got to convince every single person who sees it that it's worth their time. Keep this in mind when making decisions about product. Less is more and if it's not immediately compelling, you've lost a potential user -- the back button is your enemy.
Fortunately, most software does such a terrible job with user experience that there are loads of markets ripe for disruption. You can win on design alone (see: hipmunk.com, seatgeek.com, instagram to name a few)</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="0300E2CD832388D2C1257904006C9617" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="A3B84E7839D596F0C12578D10057812F" name="Abstraction Distractions" startTime="2011-11-09T18:05:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>Computer science is built on a shaky tower of abstractions, but we've
been distracted by other things until we believe it is reality. And we've imposed this on our users in ways we no longer even realize. Yet as developers we have two users: the mechanical users of our software, and the people who will use this code in the future to change this software. This talk teases apart some of the tangled abstractions that have become so common they are invisible yet impact important decisions. I cover languages, tools, platforms, and burrow all the way down to fundamental concepts. This wide-ranging keynote answers these questions and more:

* Why does my keyboard look the way it does?
* Why is the iPad is the most revolutionary device in the last 30 years?
* Why do some people hate Maven so much? 
* Is hiding always a good thing?</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="1B7778A85BC08E6CC12578D100576D07" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="5EE854B6A2917ED7C12578C000747241" name="Embracing Uncertainty - the Hardest Pattern of All" startTime="2011-11-10T08:30:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>Agile calls for us to embrace uncertainty, and we are desperately uncomfortable with uncertainty. So much so that we will replace it with anything, even things we know don’t work.Over the last year or so Dan has been studying and talking about patterns of effective software delivery. In this talk he explains why Embracing Uncertainty is the most fundamental effectiveness pattern of all, and offers advice to help make uncertainty less scary. He is pretty sure he won’t succeed.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="E032F082D5681850C12578C000742B1D" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="24C6365B8611BB97C125787F00699FE5" name="Stack Overflow: Social Software for the Anti-Social Part II: Electric Boogaloo" startTime="2011-11-11T08:30:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Business" />
					</tags>
					<description>It is one of the top 500 sites on the internet. A synthesis of wiki, blog, forum, and Digg/Reddit, Stack Overflow is a free programming Q A site, collaboratively built and maintained by fellow programmers. Programmers are not exactly known for being a social bunch, and yet, Stack Overflow counts over 140,000 registered users today, who asked and answered almost 2 million questions. In this talk, Jeff Atwood will share his experience designing Stack Overflow, making social software for the anti-social.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="068AF23FE90C8231C125787F006999E3" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="68EE1E34815E4307C12578FE00799138" name="From Solid to Liquid to Air, Cyborg Anthropology and the Future of the Interface" startTime="2011-11-11T16:20:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Augmented Reality" />
						<tag name="BIG picture" />
						<tag name="Design" />
						<tag name="Design Thinking" />
						<tag name="geek culture" />
						<tag name="Geo-fencing" />
						<tag name="Geo-location" />
						<tag name="history" />
						<tag name="Location" />
						<tag name="systems thinking" />
						<tag name="Smart phone" />
						<tag name="UI" />
						<tag name="UX" />
					</tags>
					<description>This speech will discuss how the field of anthropology can be applied to interface design, and how future interfaces, such as the ones employed by augmented reality, will change the way we act, feel and communicate with one another. Topics will include non-places, time and space compression, privacy, user flow, supermodernity, wearable computing, work and play, gaming, history and prosthetic culture.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="3DDF11112996AA34C12578FE0078FCB1" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
			</sessions>
		</track>
		<track name="Nservice bus">
			<sessions>
				<session id="37A6EEB78134E60EC1257920004759F4" name="Enterprise development with NServiceBus" startTime="2011-11-07T09:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="360">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>This course teaches you all the ins-and-outs of NServiceBus - the most popular, open-source service bus for .NET. Used in production since 2006, NServiceBus is now used in hundreds of companies in finance, healthcare, retail, SaaS, web 2.0, and more.From basic one-way messaging, through publish/subscribe; providing solutions from transactions to cross-machine scale out; this hands-on course will show you how simple distributed systems development can be.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="6DFEA68E544BA287C12578B800292F75" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
			</sessions>
		</track>
		<track name="Smart phone">
			<sessions>
				<session id="87564A1304E4A437C12578C5006B248C" name="Your First Android Physics Game" startTime="2011-11-07T09:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="360">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>Working with games is a dream of many developers, but when you haven't done it before, it can be difficult to know where to start. Making games with advanced collisions and physics can then seem all but impossible.In this workshop, we will show you how to get started with developing games for Android. We will start with simple concepts like sprites and layers and will finish by including a competent physics engine. The end result will be a simple physics-based game that can be used as a template for bigger and more ambitious projects.This workshop is for developers with a basic knowledge of java, but no former experience in game development is needed.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="E0DADC8949FC97DFC12578C400266558" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="BA3E98A260EBA4B2C12578CD006BB05E" name="Animation facilities in Cocoa Touch" startTime="2011-11-08T09:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="360">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>Touch-responsive smooth animations are a key component of the iOS user experience. This workshop will teach you how to use the animation facilities in Cocoa Touch to make your apps just as snappy and intuitive as Apple's own! By writing code together, we'll get to know the frameworks and find ways to add the right kinds of polish to make your apps shine. You'll also learn what sort of graphics are best suited for animation in iOS.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="3B4C30B59413441AC12578AE002A8235" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="448A5A17655B1B37C12578AF0044AEB0" name="Open data and smartphones" startTime="2011-11-09T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description></description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="1EFBE15315022B1FC12578AF004418A2" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="E328F14770F95F3AC12578B9005D608F" name="Smartphone apps for business use — a case study" startTime="2011-11-09T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Android" />
						<tag name="API" />
						<tag name="Architecture" />
						<tag name="backend programming" />
						<tag name="iOS" />
						<tag name="iPad" />
						<tag name="iPhone" />
						<tag name="Methodology" />
						<tag name="Objective-C" />
						<tag name="REST" />
						<tag name="Ruby on Rails" />
						<tag name="Smart phone" />
					</tags>
					<description>Describes the Helios framework created by Jayway for the 3Business app. It allows smartphone apps on several platforms to be dynamically configured at runtime, based on a server-provided configuration sent to each phone on startup.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="D7668B77A184B6C7C12578B9005D0895" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="E59E11A05FF49B25C12578AE002BE32C" name="Working with the Frameworks" startTime="2011-11-09T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Android" />
						<tag name="Apple" />
						<tag name="Architecture" />
						<tag name="iOS" />
						<tag name="iPad" />
						<tag name="iPhone" />
						<tag name="Java" />
						<tag name="Objective-C" />
						<tag name="Smart phone" />
						<tag name="Tablet" />
					</tags>
					<description>In many ways Android and iOS development is similar. Deception ally similar, making it easy to get caught in propblems that can easily be avoided with some knowledge of the target platform. In this session you will learn how to avoid these pit-falls. Ultimately turning the platform differences into your and the users advantage, by working with, not against the frameworks.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="988356A604BCD3A6C12578C300296950" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="EEC18AF699D6610CC12578AE002AB941" name="Become a Block-head! Advanced Objective-C block usage patterns on iOS" startTime="2011-11-09T14:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Apple" />
						<tag name="API" />
						<tag name="iOS" />
						<tag name="iPad" />
						<tag name="iPhone" />
						<tag name="Objective-C" />
						<tag name="Smart phone" />
					</tags>
					<description>Apple's addition of Block syntax to the C language (and by extension, Objective-C and C++) gives developers a powerful new tool, similar to the closures and lambdas popularized by modern scripting languages. In this talk, you'll see how to use the Block-ready APIs that Apple provides, and then learn how to make use of Blocks to improve your own code's structure and readability, including several usage patterns that go deeper than the examples set by Apple's own APIs.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="3B4C30B59413441AC12578AE002A8235" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="EE19DEB2B2922503C125785C0000EF84" name="Location Enabled Sensors for iOS: Making use of the sensors on your iPhone and iPad" startTime="2011-11-09T15:40:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Accelerometer" />
						<tag name="Apple" />
						<tag name="AR" />
						<tag name="Augmented Reality" />
						<tag name="Core Location" />
						<tag name="Core Motion" />
						<tag name="Geo-fencing" />
						<tag name="Geo-location" />
						<tag name="Gyroscope" />
						<tag name="iOS" />
						<tag name="iPad" />
						<tag name="iPhone" />
						<tag name="Location" />
						<tag name="Magnetometer" />
						<tag name="Sensors" />
						<tag name="Smart phone" />
					</tags>
					<description>This class will guide you through developing location aware applications for the iOS platforms that make use of the onboard sensors: the 3-axis accelerometer, the magnetometer, the gyroscope, the camera and the on GPS. You’ll learn how to make use of these onboard sensors and combine them to build sophisticated location aware applications. This will give you the background to building your own applications independently using the hottest location-aware technology yet for any mobile platforms.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="0CE18D33C0D2E936C12578C3005BC6F5" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="883C0E703CED03AFC12578B9005DF458" name="Designing Graceful, Gracious Interfaces for iPad" startTime="2011-11-09T16:45:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Apple" />
						<tag name="Design" />
						<tag name="iOS" />
						<tag name="iPad" />
						<tag name="Objective-C" />
						<tag name="Smart phone" />
						<tag name="UI" />
						<tag name="UX" />
					</tags>
					<description>With the iPad, full-fledged touch computing is here. What can your touch interface do better? Which of your interaction assumptions are debris you should jettison, and which still apply? When you carve away the mouse and keyboard and desktop trappings, what is your software really about? Learn how the iPad experience respects users' concentration and creativity. Find out how the iPad is distinct from its iPhone and Mac siblings, and why it requires new thinking about interaction design.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="4FDA3AC0B8F1F4F6C12578B9005DCB11" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="8129DA88112D99A7C125792400363125" name="Building Mobile Phone Applications in the Cloud" startTime="2011-11-11T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Cloud Computing" />
						<tag name="C#" />
						<tag name="iOS" />
						<tag name="iPad" />
						<tag name="iPhone" />
						<tag name="Java" />
						<tag name="Smart phone" />
						<tag name="Windows Azure" />
					</tags>
					<description>Learn how to build mobile applications for Windows Phone 7, iOS, and Android that are backed by scalable cloud components hosted in Windows Azure. This demo-focused session will cover the end-to-end experience and address how to tackle issues such as authentication, storage, and notification using the Windows Azure Toolkit for Windows Phone 7, iOS, and Android.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="2A202A7C54362AC0C12578C00065ECC5" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="8711D53118301563C12578B9005EA2B4" name="Advanced API design: how an awesome API can attract friends, make you rich, and change the world" startTime="2011-11-11T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Android" />
						<tag name="API" />
						<tag name="iOS" />
						<tag name="iPad" />
						<tag name="iPhone" />
					</tags>
					<description>APIs are becoming ubiquitous, but they are really hard to design well. In this talk, we'll discuss how to design and implement an API that isn't just functional, but makes people stand up and cheer. We'll also cover tips for integrating with other people's APIs.

But an awesome API isn't just a feature. APIs are currently transforming the world, just like open source software has changed the world for the last decade. We'll talk about how this transformation impacts developers and changes the rules.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="97471AC6BF30886AC12578C6006B0638" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="083D612F52FFD902C12578C3004D1EDC" name="How hackers attack your smartphones and tablets" startTime="2011-11-11T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Smart phone" />
					</tags>
					<description>This live-demo session will show actual examples of how attackers could gain full control over your smartphone or tablet; enabling them to steal sensitive data, use it as audio recording device for eavesdropping, or remote-control your device to send SMS messages, place phone calls, and much more. The demos will also show why such attacks are likely to be left undetected by antivirus products, and that the malware could even remain after a factory reset or firmware update.
Users as well as IT managers are getting more and more concerned about protecting their assets on mobile devices, and I will talk about several built-in security mechanisms that could improve the overall security if configured correctly</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="4026DF0B8DF6B13AC12578C3004C9AF5" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="D0BAA040F9497D72C1257927002728F6" name="Realworld XNA on Windows Phone" startTime="2011-11-11T14:05:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="C#" />
						<tag name="Smart phone" />
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>With XNA it's possible to write once and deploy on three platform: PC, XBox and Windows Phone. This talk will go into the depths of XNA on Windows Phone. You will learn the tricks of the trade from real published projects. Additionally, you will learn how to port applications from iPhone to Windows Phone with minimal effort.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="D4F59D75FC378DBFC125792700271A06" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="BA8BF8116C677C15C12578C400520004" name="Are we carrying horses in our pockets? Designing secure applications for smart phones." startTime="2011-11-11T15:15:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Android" />
						<tag name="BIG picture" />
						<tag name="BlackBerry" />
						<tag name="Business" />
						<tag name="iOS" />
						<tag name="Smart phone" />
					</tags>
					<description></description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="957174DC42E095DCC12578CB0024044D" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
			</sessions>
		</track>
		<track name="TDD">
			<sessions>
				<session id="313DD8CB44125BB2C12578FF0048E5DD" name="Improving your TDD" startTime="2011-11-07T09:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="360">
					<tags>
						<tag name="C#" />
						<tag name="Design" />
						<tag name="Design Thinking" />
						<tag name="Dev excellence" />
						<tag name="Dev.Excellence" />
						<tag name="Java" />
						<tag name="object orientation" />
						<tag name="ruby" />
						<tag name="Ruby on Rails" />
						<tag name="software craftsmanship" />
						<tag name="Test" />
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>In this day-long workshop, we'll explore some more subtle aspects of test-driven development. Through intense, hands-on exercises, we'll look at aspects of TDD that are often overlooked, including:- what effect does test ordering have on your design;- how do you choose the next test to write;- the effect of isolation-based testing on your design.This workshop is language-agnostic, although focused on object-oriented languages. So, come spend the day exploring through code.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="33A9B170937DDE76C12578C900660087" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="4D2F827AC7F1D97CC12578C9006906F7" name="Come introduce yourself to the concepts and fundamental technique behind TDD" startTime="2011-11-08T09:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="360">
					<tags>
						<tag name="C#" />
						<tag name="Dev excellence" />
						<tag name="Dev.Excellence" />
						<tag name="Java" />
						<tag name="Methodology" />
						<tag name="object orientation" />
						<tag name="Other Languages" />
						<tag name="Ruby on Rails" />
						<tag name="Test" />
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>Test-driven development is a core practice of software craftsmanship and professional software development. Getting started on your own is difficult, though. In this extremely hands-on course, we will cover basic concepts and techniques around test-first and test-driven development, as well as explicit practices to get you started. Along the way, we'll talk about the benefits and values you can provide to your clients, businesses and team members through effective usage of test-driven development.Topics covered:Test-first vs Test-driven developmentBuilding blocks of testingUsing tests to drive designUsing your regression test suite</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="33A9B170937DDE76C12578C900660087" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
			</sessions>
		</track>
		<track name="Test">
			<sessions>
				<session id="7C7E10769874C7D2C12578A40015D5F1" name="Agile Team Flow" startTime="2011-11-07T09:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="360">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="Business" />
						<tag name="Context driven" />
						<tag name="Dev excellence" />
						<tag name="Games" />
						<tag name="Methodology" />
						<tag name="Test" />
					</tags>
					<description>While some companies are fully committed to adopting Agile, others are adopting it in name only. Some Agile teams flourish, while others can barely move ahead. Come learn about agile project delivery and how high-performing agile teams flow. In this interactive tutorial we will experience what it is like to work on agile teams, both good and bad, and discover what it takes to grow a strong Agile team. You will leave with valuable insights and practical techniques you can readily apply at work.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="353467906EBCF349C12578A4000D8D92" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="4BE85AE083A9C33EC125787F00784A3D" name="Transitioning to Agile Testing" startTime="2011-11-08T09:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="360">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Test" />
					</tags>
					<description>Transitioning to Agile Testing Did you ever wonder what a tester does on an agile team? There are no formal written requirements documents from which to create test cases, and the features aren’t complete before they need to be tested. It can be confusing for testers who are new to agile teams. New agile development project teams often don’t understand how beneficial having a tester can be to the overall success of the project.In this tutorial, we’ll follow an agile tester through a typical two-week iteration, and more. We start with how testers contribute during release and iteration planning, and then follow a tester from the start, through to the end of an iteration to see what activities he does and how he adds value. Exercises and discussions will reinforce the learning. Finally, we examine the agile tester’s role in a successful release, including the end game, UAT, packaging, and documentation.Any tester who is struggling to understand their role on an agile team, functional managers, or other members of an agile team (developers, iteration managers, product owners) wanting to know how to get all their stories, including all testing tasks, “done” by the end of each iteration, will find value in this tutorial.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="889EB8F85EA67F96C125785A0009AE65" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="D6C9A9762E91FF80C12578CC0028F7CA" name="How I wish users knew how I help them through context driven testing" startTime="2011-11-10T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="collaboration" />
						<tag name="Context driven" />
						<tag name="management" />
						<tag name="passion" />
						<tag name="systems thinking" />
						<tag name="Test" />
					</tags>
					<description>This talk will be about the journey of being a context driven tester and the opposition I faced and how I paddled through it to win in most of my assignments. People think I did it wrong. I was aggressive on people to change their thought process to context driven thinking. I realized that when I win their heart, I also could win their brain.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="B1462034B67D0A0AC12578CC0027F4AF" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="AB4123B3E48E385AC125785B00686A0E" name="Case Study on Team Leadership with Context-Driven Exploratory Tests" startTime="2011-11-10T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Context driven" />
						<tag name="Methodology" />
						<tag name="Test" />
					</tags>
					<description>What's the effect of exploratory testing on a Team? What effect the practice has on their leader?Shmuel’s team experience in user centered Context-Driven projects made them realize that more than technical practice, it calls for change in leadership style and interactions.This dynamic talk tells a story of innovation in methods, deliverables and management. More than that, it tells a story of people, excellence, skills and satisfaction. If you have a testing team, and you want to see an alternative for team operations that maximize their potential and satisfaction, this talk is for you.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="C0B2C00315F18E98C125785B00652857" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="210CB448766FC092C125788E0069D7DB" name="Sleeping with the enemy" startTime="2011-11-10T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Methodology" />
						<tag name="Test" />
					</tags>
					<description>Traditional software delivery models are based on a lack of trust. Because the business doesn't trust developers, testers are asked to provide independent validation. Because developers don't trust testers, everyone wastes a lot of time arguing about whether a problem is in the code or in the tests. And testers are taught not to trust anyone! All of this distrust even though we share the same end-goal—delivering a product that satisfies our customers. Gojko Adzic describes why independent testing should be a thing of the past. He explains how testers engaging with developers and business users create opportunities to accomplish things they cannot do otherwise. Learn how delivery—from small web start-ups to large financial institutions—facilitate good communication and trust among business users, testers, and developers to deliver better software, faster.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="A6132D1B068B2536C125788E00688E8E" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="9FB2D5A70F8BC22AC12578C10045846B" name="Diversity in team composition" startTime="2011-11-10T14:05:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Context driven" />
						<tag name="Test" />
					</tags>
					<description>A tester is a tester or is it so? Let's have a look at team composition. There are several schools of thoughts on this matter. Along with a strong agile movement come a popular believe that it today is necessary for a tester to have strong programing skills. I do not disagree that programing skills can be beneficial in a test team but there is so much more to it then that. Another example is that many companies require their testers to be ISTQB certified. I se a pattern that we tend to uniform our testers, we want them all to be the same preferable copies of a pre defined role description. Many in the test community has previous claimed that a problem with testers is that we do not have enough or the right skills and that the solution is programing and certifications. What i now see is that we are beginning to lose something precious among us testers, that is diversity. Testing is the art of investigation and searching, we do not know what we are looking for and we do not know where it is hiding. To be great at this we need different skills and a team of diversified testers. We like to be prepared to approach our test object from many different angles and to analyze it's feedback with from different viewpoints. We should not look for unity when composing our test team instead we appreciate diversity and when looking for skills don't forget to look outside the technical area and the most obvious so called testing skills.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="7645723878860845C12578AE00312BB3" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="E4CCF5C2578D9A5CC12578A400140651" name="Focusing Testing on Business Needs" startTime="2011-11-10T15:15:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="Business" />
						<tag name="Context driven" />
						<tag name="Methodology" />
						<tag name="Test" />
					</tags>
					<description>Testers often forget that they are service providers whose role is to provide critical information to the project’s stakeholders. Testing must focus on business needs to add the most value and gain respect. Attend to discover communication techniques that will help testers connect with stakeholders and get them clamoring for more testing. Leave with real-world approaches for handling difficult conversations and project situations that will gain the respect of stakeholders.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="353467906EBCF349C12578A4000D8D92" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="91CE39281D6B1570C125787F0076A016" name="Artful Testing" startTime="2011-11-10T16:20:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Test" />
					</tags>
					<description>Art and testing may look like an odd couple. True, Glenford Myers combined both in his book “The Art of Software Testing”, but the art in there was strictly limited to the title page, since the term isn’t even mentioned once throughout the whole book. It referred to skill and mastery, of course, not to an aesthetic experience. More recently, Robert Austin and Lee Devin published “Artful making” which mainly addressed software development and its resemblance to art. This got me thinking: what about artful testing?In this presentation I will investigate what happens when we infuse testing with aesthetics. Can the fine arts in any way support or complement our testing efforts? With some surprising examples, I will illustrate that I think they can.The tools used by art critics, for instance, can be a valuable addition to our tester toolbox. They enable us to become software critics, engaging in demystification and deconstruction. Testers can also benefit from studying art and looking at it. After all, this largely resembles what we do when we are testing: thoughtfully looking at software. Art carries the risk of being mistaken for superficial “look and see”, as does testing: we look; we see what’s there – or we believe we do. But looking at something in ways that make sense of it calls for much more than that. It appeals to our experiental and reflective intelligence. Art feeds and stimulates the tester’s hungry eye. As we are overloaded with greater amounts of information than ever before, our ability to find meaning in things surrounding us involves a complex set of thinking skills. Naming what we see is one of them. Analyzing context based on personal association and perspective, cultural knowledge, interpretation, evidence, imagination, exploration and risk is another. These questioning and reasoning strategies used in evaluating art can be applied in testing too. This is where testing and art can meet. Good testing should be artful, in so many ways.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="88FF9BB4674FE7A8C125787F007680B4" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="7A406EB55BA22761C125785A000B5EC2" name="Agile Testing: Advanced Topics" startTime="2011-11-11T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="Context driven" />
						<tag name="Test" />
					</tags>
					<description>Your team successfully adopted Agile and you have traction on practices such as CI, TDD, maybe ATDD. Still, you see lots of room for improvement in testing? In this talk, Janet will share some practices to better understand and capture customer needs, collaborate more effectively and enjoyably with team members, and some ideas how to test on big agile projects.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="889EB8F85EA67F96C125785A0009AE65" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="2479AD967DCEE6AEC125790D006AEAB3" name="Curing Our Binary Disease" startTime="2011-11-11T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="humanistic" />
						<tag name="passion" />
						<tag name="Test" />
					</tags>
					<description>Software testing is too computeresque; we suffer a pass/fail addiction, with coverage obsession, metrics tumor and sick test design techniques. We can liberate ourselves and look at diverse information sources, uncovering what is important. We can investigate software as humans, make subjective judgments and handle the inevitable unknown. We can get rid of the numbers, and communicate noteworthy interpretations of what is important.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="466FF005B0C0B40AC125790D006793F5" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="46394B111077CFF9C12578AE007F9481" name="Automated Acceptance Testing Anti-patterns" startTime="2011-11-11T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="Test" />
					</tags>
					<description>In this session, we analyze the anatomy of an automated acceptance test, after which look at actual cases of repeated abuse of the written specification, its testability, or the underlying implementation – hence anti-patterns.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="54FE6EE9F0C514ADC12578AE007A39FF" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="5DE7FF0CD24D5808C125786300794A87" name="Time Off For Good Behaviour: Getting the Most Out of Your BDD Tests" startTime="2011-11-11T14:05:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="Business" />
						<tag name="Test" />
					</tags>
					<description>To get the most out of Behaviour Driven Development (BDD), you need much more than a tool.You need high value specifications.How do we get the most out of our specification and test writing effort? How do we turn vague business-speak into testable scenarios? These and other questions will be addressed in this talk in which we take a practical approach using real-world examples.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="D379E52E40B16BF3C125786300774F86" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="1D857F976E8500F5C125788E0068CE93" name="Visualising quality" startTime="2011-11-11T15:15:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="Business" />
						<tag name="Methodology" />
						<tag name="Test" />
					</tags>
					<description>Defect tracking is useless, creating reports on bug trends is a waste of time. QA people who really want to present their business stakeholders with useful information need to focus on a completely different way of reporting. Join Gojko Adzic for an exploration of different ways to measure and visualise quality of software.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="A6132D1B068B2536C125788E00688E8E" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
			</sessions>
		</track>
		<track name="User Experience">
			<sessions>
				<session id="D0A5FAD1349E484AC12578B50078B069" name="How hard could it be? What’s User Experience is and isn’t" startTime="2011-11-10T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="UX" />
					</tags>
					<description>User Experience is the newish general term we give to user research, user interface design, usability engineering, and a few other sub-specialties. In the past UX work fell to a select few specialized roles – roles that didn’t fit well in many processes, especially agile processes. Over the last decade there’s been an evolution towards more whole-team thinking and a wealth of new practices that involve everyone in UX design. The session will help developers and others understand what UX is and isn't, how UX practice fits into agile process today, and why it was such a challenge to get it to fit in the first place.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="0F5612DF26331F1AC12578640020C3F0" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="DF4FEA9DDA1F51BCC125793000372426" name="Participation in Mixed Reality" startTime="2011-11-10T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="UX" />
					</tags>
					<description>This talk will focus on users with disabilities and their experiences in a more and more mixed reality. Drawing on and showing examples from several projects on games, tangible computing and mobile interaction I will try to pinpoint human and technological factors that can help or hinder users from participating in fun and challenging activities. As part of this, I will also show how we have done to engage children with intellectual disabilities as co-designers in our development and design processes.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="8A7B0A92BF53F35EC12579300036FA16" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="4148603365A07541C12578800051B8CB" name="Fonts, Form and Function: A Primer on Digital Typography" startTime="2011-11-10T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="UX" />
					</tags>
					<description>Typography in digital experiences is unavoidable, and for years it was a fight we mostly lost. Today, however, technology is on our side! High resolution screens, an expanding library of open fonts and new flexibility in nearly every UI technology have made digital typography more fun and more interesting than ever. We'll cover all aspects of working with digital type: everything from choosing complimentary typefaces to licensing, rendering and a system for layout and sizing. We all love type. Come to this talk to learn why!</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="FBEA087794522C56C125788000519436" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="7E545C7191C48890C12578800051AAB2" name="Design Composition for Developers" startTime="2011-11-10T14:05:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="UX" />
					</tags>
					<description>This workshop introduces you to composition, one of the most fundamental principles of design. The workshop is tuned especially for people who have some background in coding. If you are a developer who is working more frequently with designers, evolving to become a designer yourself, or simply a manager who needs to make sure that both roles work smoothly together, this session is an invaluable opportunity to jump-start the process.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="FBEA087794522C56C125788000519436" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="D6774C3C859682F9C12578BD004A8AEE" name="Winning the long term user - with analytics" startTime="2011-11-10T15:15:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="Business" />
						<tag name="game-ification" />
						<tag name="iPad" />
						<tag name="Methodology" />
						<tag name="Tablet" />
						<tag name="UX" />
						<tag name="Visualization" />
					</tags>
					<description>Very often when developers think about user experience and user satisfaction we focus on short term issues. Of course it is fascinating and useful to create a great, easy-to-learn environment for new users. But it is our long-term users who become champions of the product and can be our most valuable customers. How often do we think about the needs of advanced users who work with the product every day? How do we keep them productive? And how do we keep them interested, challenged and engaged?</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="98389B108A5E77C8C12578BD0048928C" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="77985AB7C2E715D5C12578C6008136CC" name="From Mac to iPhone to iPad (And Back)" startTime="2011-11-10T16:20:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Apple" />
						<tag name="Design" />
						<tag name="iOS" />
						<tag name="iPad" />
						<tag name="iPhone" />
						<tag name="UI" />
						<tag name="UX" />
					</tags>
					<description>Bringing an application from the desktop to a touch device, or vice versa, is never simple. You must reconsider every last interaction from scratch. But the underlying data, and the user's mental model, need to remain the same. Learn how we brought our full-featured Mac productivity apps to iPhone and iPad, and made them feel like they were meant to be there all along. And even better, hear about the lessons we learned on iOS and that we are now bringing back to the desktop.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="4FDA3AC0B8F1F4F6C12578B9005DCB11" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
			</sessions>
		</track>
		<track name="Web">
			<sessions>
				<session id="717AEBAA1E52DF31C12578B7004EF7B0" name="Creative JavaScript and HTML 5" startTime="2011-11-07T09:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="720">
					<tags>
						<tag name="HTML5" />
						<tag name="JavaScript" />
						<tag name="Visualization" />
						<tag name="Web Dev" />
					</tags>
					<description>We’ll start off with the basics of rendering into an HTML5 canvas, and animating simple objects. We'll then learn that physics simulations don't need to be rocket science. And what better way to use physics than to make a particle system with sparks, smoke and explosions?Working in two dimensions is one thing but three is one better! We'll demystify 3D rendering by creating our own simple 3D system. And then move on to more complex examples using three.js library from Mr.doob and his team.We’ll also examine the differences between using canvas, and DOM elements to help choose which one is right for us.Finally we'll use these new found abilities to make a simple game.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="6038141F4C3D476BC1257880004BF72F" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="0FBF741241EAD9B9C1257880004C062D" name="Creative javascript effects" startTime="2011-11-09T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="JavaScript" />
						<tag name="UX" />
						<tag name="Visualization" />
						<tag name="Web Dev" />
					</tags>
					<description>Now that the open standards Canvas and SVG are available natively in all major browsers, JavaScript developers have much to learn about creative visual programming.From particle systems to blending effects, optimised animations, 3D, touch interfaces, gaming and good old maths creativity, Seb Lee-Delisle has more than a trick or two to share with us. If you’re interested in bringing a little visceral beauty to your websites, apps and games, then you will want to see this talk.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="6038141F4C3D476BC1257880004BF72F" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="B2606E05A1201790C12578AD006C1064" name="Sproutcore" startTime="2011-11-09T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="JavaScript" />
						<tag name="Web Dev" />
					</tags>
					<description>Building web applications with traditional web development techniques is painful. Making sure your HTML is always up-to-date is challenging, and swapping information back and forth with your server can be error-prone.There is a better way. SproutCore's robust bindings system allows you to create data-centric applications. Just describe the state of your application and how the data flows from your models to your views and let SproutCore do the rest.Semantic templates allow you to write HTML and CSS that update automatically when your models change—like magic. And an in-memory database lets you intelligently manage and query your data and synchronize with your server.SproutCore will change the way you think about building applications and surprise you with how little code you have to write.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="E10871750E5CA64BC12578AD006BF621" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="37B0DFDB5D01649BC12578B6002A8237" name="Websocket and Web Communication in 50 minutes" startTime="2011-11-09T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Architecture" />
						<tag name="HTML5" />
						<tag name="Java" />
						<tag name="JavaScript" />
						<tag name="Web Dev" />
						<tag name="WebSocket" />
					</tags>
					<description>HTML5 Web Sockets provide an enormous reduction in unnecessary network traffic and latency compared to the unscalable polling and long-polling solutions that were used to simulate a full-duplex connection by maintaining two connections.

HTML5 Web Sockets account for network hazards such as proxies and firewalls, making streaming possible over any connection, and with the ability to support upstream and downstream communications over a single connection, HTML5 Web Sockets-based applications place less burden on servers, allowing existing machines to support more concurrent connections.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="043666AE7B2C4F08C12578B5005BB2A9" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="B8F928690D2DAB7BC12578AD006C2103" name="Ruby On Rails" startTime="2011-11-09T14:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Web Dev" />
					</tags>
					<description>Rails is a web application development framework written in the Ruby language.
It is designed to make programming web applications easier by making
assumptions about what every developer needs. It allows you to
write less code while accomplishing more.

The latest version of Rails introduced, among other things, the asset pipeline.
It's a way to concatenate and minify or compress JavaScript and CSS assets.
Now, Rails does not only come ready for development, it comes ready for
production.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="E10871750E5CA64BC12578AD006BF621" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="B838B3B927049A15C1257880004B5B52" name="Test-driven Javascript" startTime="2011-11-09T15:40:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Agile" />
						<tag name="Architecture" />
						<tag name="JavaScript TDD" />
						<tag name="Other Languages" />
						<tag name="Test" />
						<tag name="Web Dev" />
					</tags>
					<description>Tired of being a JavaScript cowboy? Join me and learn to develop JavaScript with confidence. In this session I will take you through a live-coding TDD session while highlighting some of the unique challenges of unit testing JavaScript for the browser. The session will also shed some light on how to structure JS programs for maintainable and scalable apps, avoiding common pitfalls. Nobody likes that single huge incomprehensible .js file - I will teach you have to do away with it.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="7D515E0384273415C1257888002496B1" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="E196DB8E2E7A1184C12578A4005D2395" name="Node.js - A practical introduction" startTime="2011-11-09T16:45:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="JavaScript" />
						<tag name="node.js" />
						<tag name="Web Dev" />
					</tags>
					<description>This talk is a practical introduction to node.js, as well as an overview of the applications that are easier to build with node than using other plattforms.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="47717052A75DF501C12578A4005C7AF9" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="9FAFD7C1077CDD66C12578CC0025492D" name="0-60 with Goliath: Building High Performance Ruby Web-Services" startTime="2011-11-11T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="API" />
						<tag name="Architecture" />
						<tag name="backend programming" />
						<tag name="eventmachine" />
						<tag name="network" />
						<tag name="node.js" />
						<tag name="Other Languages" />
						<tag name="ruby" />
						<tag name="Ruby on Rails" />
						<tag name="web service" />
						<tag name="Web Dev" />
						<tag name="WebSocket" />
					</tags>
					<description>Building a high-performance web service in Ruby? Then, chances are, you are looking at implementing a non-blocking server. Goliath is an open source, event-driven I/O framework, much like node.js or Tornado, except that Goliath is based on EventMachine, features a Ruby API, and most importantly, does away with the asynchronous &quot;callback muck&quot; by utilizing Ruby 1.9’s Fibers to preserve the nice synchronous look-and-feel of your code – which makes it much easier to write, test, and maintain.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="482EA8E9642F26E7C12578CC0023E5B5" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="70277725E303264BC125789F0072EB7E" name="CoffeeScript: Design Patterns for the New JavaScript" startTime="2011-11-11T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="CoffeeScript" />
						<tag name="JavaScript" />
						<tag name="Web Dev" />
					</tags>
					<description>CoffeeScript is a relatively small and simple language. At its core, it's just JavaScript. Because its types and semantics are the same, you can use CoffeeScript with any JS library. But a little syntactic sugar goes a long way. Find out how this little language could dramatically change the way you write code.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="DD231B5D8CFED92BC125789F0059BDC0" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="EC3EE6E99A073B88C125792C00353C4E" name="Functional Javascript" startTime="2011-11-11T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="functional" />
						<tag name="JavaScript" />
						<tag name="Web Dev" />
					</tags>
					<description>Javascript has long been a misunderstood programming language. Its roots come from Self and Scheme, a prototypical and a functional programming language respectively. Not very mainstream! Yet, Javascript has evolved into one of the most widespread programming languages in the world! In this presentation you will learn what it means for a language to have first class functions and you will learn functional programming with higher order functions. I will show how to use functional programming
techniques in Javascript and how these techniques can help you organize your code.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="0D1833DC4B4121A3C125792C00350E81" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="0076CC8E75BBB90DC125789F0074488F" name="Transforming Data into Pixels: Visualization with Canvas and CoffeeScript" startTime="2011-11-11T14:05:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="CoffeeScript" />
						<tag name="Smart phone" />
						<tag name="Tablet" />
						<tag name="Visualization" />
						<tag name="Web Dev" />
					</tags>
					<description>HTML5's canvas isn't just for games. You can use those pixels for serious business, from simple charts and graphs to dynamic, interactive data visualizations that perform well across all modern browsers (including those on iOS and Android devices).Thanks to CoffeeScript and a plethora of new libraries, the once-intimidating canvas is now easily tamed. I'll show, step-by-step, how you can build a robust data visualization system that fits your site's needs.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="DD231B5D8CFED92BC125789F0059BDC0" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="605A69BAF60E20CCC12578B3003EE009" name="Under Attack, Web Application Security in Practice" startTime="2011-11-11T15:15:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Web Dev" />
					</tags>
					<description>There is a gap between the security experts and developers and their view of software development. This session will try to bridge the gap, give an overview of the current state of web application security and show ways to get security into the minds of the developers .</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="7524E50E541CCD89C12578AE00236B4C" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
			</sessions>
		</track>
		<track name="Windows 8">
			<sessions>
				<session id="CAA22B5C58D769FDC1257926003EA300" name="Intro to the Future of the Microsoft Application Development Platform: Building HTML5 Applications with Visual Studio 11 for Windows 8" startTime="2011-11-11T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>One of the most notable advances in the Developer preview releases of both Windows 8 and Visual Studio 11 is the ability to create consumer-focused, Windows Metro style apps using HTML5. Visual Studio 11 provides end-to-end support for building HTML5 apps, spanning the development, debugging, and deployment lifecycle.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="2307AEA4865142ABC1257926003E6548" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="7CD46BFCEDF6E2D0C1257926003ECBB7" name="The Next Generation of Software: Delivering Improved User Experience with Metro Style Windows 8 Applications and Leveraging the Natural User Interface" startTime="2011-11-11T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>Metro is a pillar of the upcoming Windows 8 OS. Microsoft has received numerous awards and accolades on their Metro implementation in Windows Phone 7: “The innovation here is the fluidity of experience and focus on the data, without using tradition user interface conventions of windows and frames. Data becomes the visual elements and controls. Simple gestures and transitions guide the user deeper into content. A truly elegant and unique experience.” 
Now, with Windows 8, we have the start of the new age of software focused in Metro Style Applications that leverage the Natural User Experience (NUI). 
</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="2307AEA4865142ABC1257926003E6548" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="95E6FB12AF17AE59C12579260040B912" name="Moving your XAML applications to Metro" startTime="2011-11-11T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>By now you know what Metro is, what the Windows Runtime (WinRT) is, and that C# and VB.NET can access the WinRT via an interop layer. The big question: What's involved in moving my Silverlight (or WPF) application over to Metro? In this session Carl Franklin goes through the pain points and gives you a real idea of what it will take to port your application.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="A66B776EE4F4D1E9C125792600406EB6" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="E0730206FE39A422C1257926003F3C5A" name="Ubiquitous Services: Building the Backbone for your Desktop, Mobile and Metro apps with WCF Web API" startTime="2011-11-11T14:05:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>With the rising interest and need for mobile and touch-enabled applications we need a profound base to model services in order to provide access to remote business logic and data for our client applications - cross-device cross-platform. By leveraging the power of HTTP (REST anyone?) we can use the new WCF Web API to expose services in a webstyle way for targeting different kinds of applications. Including your desktop applications, your new mobile apps as well as Windows 8's Metro-style apps.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="DE7128AB58732BAFC1257926003F1B7F" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="ED14E910EB053FFEC1257926003FDA8B" name=".NET Rocks Live Panel Discussion on WinRT" startTime="2011-11-11T15:15:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>Join Carl Franklin and Richard Campbell for a panel discussion on the WinRT, the new run time for Windows 8. Is this the death of Silverlight? What about .NET? Do we all have to develop in HTML 5 now? Bring your questions and get the scoop on what’s really happening with Windows 8 and what some of the best and brightest in the Microsoft development space are planning to do around Windows 8. You’ll be part of a .NET Rocks Live show!</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="AC217FE86663C99BC1257926003FB37B" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
			</sessions>
		</track>
		<track name="Workshops">
			<sessions>
				<session id="9BB5548F03A40221C12578CD00757CF6" name="No not cars, CQRS one day workshop" startTime="2011-11-07T09:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="360">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>CQRS has been being picked up by many people due toits ability to help simplify complex domains. This workshop willintroduce CQRS as well as Event Sourcing. An existing stereotypicalarchitecture will be evolved into one using CQRS and Event Sourcingwith many interesting architectures along the way. We will also divedeep into real working code how different aspects of the systemactually work with a very heavy emphasis on not only how to produceworking code but also how to test it.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="53988259A9936183C125787F006B2920" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="BF66446534EF9260C12578FB00353780" name="No not cars, CQRS one day WS" startTime="2011-11-08T09:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="360">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>CQRS has been being picked up by many people due toits ability to help simplify complex domains. This workshop willintroduce CQRS as well as Event Sourcing. An existing stereotypicalarchitecture will be evolved into one using CQRS and Event Sourcingwith many interesting architectures along the way. We will also divedeep into real working code how different aspects of the systemactually work with a very heavy emphasis on not only how to produceworking code but also how to test it.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="53988259A9936183C125787F006B2920" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
			</sessions>
		</track>
		<track name="Xtra(ck)">
			<sessions>
				<session id="A13029632C047A9FC1257899003FB139" name="Gamification - the art of making fun that piece of reality wich is routine, boring or mundane." startTime="2011-11-09T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Games" />
					</tags>
					<description>How game and game mechanics can help you create a better user experience.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="DB19F3CF5F9B06D4C1257899003F8563" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="6C40A7D674D20C60C12578A000486BB7" name="RFID Security Case Study - Rejsekortet" startTime="2011-11-09T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Hackers" />
						<tag name="Public Sector" />
						<tag name="RFID" />
						<tag name="Smart phone" />
					</tags>
					<description>An overview of RFID implemented in real world applications, basic RFID security, Rejsekortet as a case study. Practical tools for cloning RFID cards.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="00DF42A089DAE7CBC12578A000479A73" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="BD5A0602D2973F89C12578AE0050C169" name="What a RepRap is and how hardware construction works with Open Source" startTime="2011-11-09T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Hackers" />
					</tags>
					<description>A description of what a RepRap is (Selfassembly hobby 3D printer), and how it is constructed (using the open source drawings) with some purchased parts them self being Open Source.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="C96AE9642B9D782AC12578AE004F7BE9" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="CCCE21BCD66194DAC12578C4005BA58D" name="Using Technology to Create a Global Network of Filmmakers" startTime="2011-11-09T14:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="animation" />
						<tag name="art" />
						<tag name="artist" />
						<tag name="best dressed speaker" />
						<tag name="collaboration" />
						<tag name="creativity" />
						<tag name="film" />
						<tag name="Location" />
						<tag name="passion" />
						<tag name="remote collaboration" />
						<tag name="youth" />
					</tags>
					<description>Will is a young film maker who will be sharing his experiences of the film making process using remote collaboration. Guaranteed to be illuminating and insightful into how young people today are utilizing technology in order to enhance the creative process.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="3DF1D48DE8680ABBC125790D00261584" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="AB76551F855B5EDAC12578C4004AA873" name="Photowalk: learning shooting techniques in Malmö" startTime="2011-11-09T15:40:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>Come for a photowalk and explore Malmö through the viewfinder of your camera. You will learn to see with the eye of the photographer, use the rule of thirds, understand how light and color can be used effectively, and have a shared, fun experience.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="F0EDAADBD99BBC4AC1257880001E2AAB" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="825E07F588E2D551C12578AE003AA4DD" name="Basic beginner tips for better pictures" startTime="2011-11-09T16:45:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>During one hour session you'll get different tips on how to take more interesting and appealing pictures. We start off by learning the basics of how a camera works and how we can use that knowledge to take better och different pictures. After that we'll go through basic tips about light, colors and perspective. Last but not least you'll try to use this new knowledge and take three different pictures and together we'll look at them and I will give some comments.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="36B93A9D0E00ACE6C12578A0003F23E6" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="D2678662BC7565BEC125788F0057698E" name="The next generation Internet users" startTime="2011-11-10T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="usage" />
					</tags>
					<description>What are the trends when it comes to the use of Internet and media among teenagers and kids? What are the typical youth behaviors today that will follow them through the rest of their lives, and what can we expect will change when they grow up to be adults? We can see youngsters using Internet in different ways than older generations, does this mean will see some technologies and services disappear over time?</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="Unknown" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="E8020BD5089253BBC12578930034C368" name="Geek feminism: Where did it come from and what's it all about?" startTime="2011-11-10T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="geek culture" />
						<tag name="geek feminism" />
						<tag name="history" />
						<tag name="social activism" />
					</tags>
					<description>The geek feminism movement is growing all around the world, in fields as diverse as open source programming, science fiction literature and live action role playing. Who are the geek feminists, and what do they want? Teresa Axner has spent years spreading the word of gender equality throughout the Scandinavian gaming scene. In this session she gives a brief history of geek feminism, in an international as well as local context. Naturally, everyone is very welcome - regardless of gender.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="F45A29D023E1E908C1257893002FFA08" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="C19F6755F6D30F97C125789A002659D3" name="Book Reading: Test-Driven JavaScript Development" startTime="2011-11-10T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>Christian Johansen will tell us about is book: Test-Driven JavaScript Development</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="7D515E0384273415C1257888002496B1" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="723A4176495B516BC12578CC0027053F" name="Intelligent Code: Getting Started with Machine Learning" startTime="2011-11-10T14:05:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="big data" />
						<tag name="Cloud Computing" />
						<tag name="Complexity Theory" />
						<tag name="Data" />
						<tag name="Data Scientist" />
						<tag name="Hackers" />
						<tag name="Infographics" />
						<tag name="machine learning" />
						<tag name="ruby" />
						<tag name="Sensors" />
					</tags>
					<description>Machine learning is a discipline that is concerned with the design and development of algorithms that allow computers to evolve behaviors based on empirical data — a fancy name for a simple concept. Behind all the buzzword algorithms such as Decision Trees, Singular Value Decomposition, and Support Vector Machines lie simple observations and principles. In this presentation, we will take a ground-up look at how they work, and how you can apply them in your own applications.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="482EA8E9642F26E7C12578CC0023E5B5" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="005240EE6C625991C12578990032386D" name="Get rich, in time" startTime="2011-11-10T15:15:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>Sociologist Jörgen Larsson will talk about different dimensions of temporal well-being. The presentation will be based on recent studies of fathers (of whom some are working in the IT-sector) choosing uncommon strategies for living a more fulfilling life. You will get to know what these time-pioneers are doing, what the costs and benefits are of their choices, and whether YOU could do this is you decided to.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="A58974023A9DA684C125788F003DF160" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="94C982708118B632C125792E003FDB70" name="Information and Internet Activism" startTime="2011-11-10T16:20:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="" />
					</tags>
					<description>How the digital world changes our privacy, access to information and consumer culture. Through real-world practical examples, we will try to guide you to a set of best practices.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="F37E41500819E43BC125792E003F75E3" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
			</sessions>
		</track>
		<track name=".NET">
			<sessions>
				<session id="F8420099F5A5275CC12578B80029B06F" name="Enterprise development with NServiceBus" startTime="2011-11-08T09:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="360">
					<tags>
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>This course teaches you all the ins-and-outs of NServiceBus - the most popular, open-source service bus for .NET. Used in production since 2006, NServiceBus is now used in hundreds of companies in finance, healthcare, retail, SaaS, web 2.0, and more.
From basic one-way messaging, through publish/subscribe; providing solutions from transactions to cross-machine scale out; this hands-on course will show you how simple distributed systems development can be.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="6DFEA68E544BA287C12578B800292F75" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="53D9EFC6E24EC27EC12578B7006BC111" name="Async 101" startTime="2011-11-09T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>In this session we will discuss what asynchrony is all about and why we need to use asynchronous calls at all. We'll look at why the existing approaches are messy, and how C# 5 addresses this with async methods. We'll discuss how they're applicable to both server and client code, and take a peek under the covers to see where the magic comes from.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="9428A6E3C0EADE3BC12578B7006B4D2F" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="C16C4187B3839451C12578BD0033C71C" name=".NET Collections Deep Dive" startTime="2011-11-09T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>The .Net framework provides a rich set of collection classes, but how much do you really know about them? In this presentation we’ll take a deep dive into the .Net 4.0 collection classes and examine which are best for what scenario and why. By the end of the presentation, you’ll no longer be happy just reaching for the same old collection you always have before, but you’ll be armed with the information required to pick the best collection for your needs.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="7D13AA6B3FB4DE0EC12578BD0033B1DC" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="30ADFEED47C7D71AC12578BD0039A348" name="Building ReSTful APIs, and how learning the word hypermedia will make you look smarter" startTime="2011-11-09T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>Hypermedia is the most powerful aspect of the web, a tried and tested technology that lets you link things with other things. This session will start from a poorly designed, RPC-style API and evolve it by introducing links and forms, resulting in decreased coupling, leaner clients and happier users.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="2DA76E8016569F70C12578BD0039914B" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="4B24C7522EF7599CC12578B00046A1D2" name="Building mobile web applications using ASP.NET MVC 4, HTML 5, and jQuery Mobile" startTime="2011-11-09T14:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>There are over a billion mobile devices with rich Web capabilities, yet many Websites look terrible on such devices. As mobile devices become the primary way that most people access the Web, having a site that fails to deliver a rich experience on the Web using HTML5, JavaScript and jQuery Mobile is missing out. In this session, learn how ASP.NET MVC 4 leverages these technologies enabling developers to build a single solution that targets multiple platforms and form factors.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="88DE8E0DC68D646CC12578B0004652C0" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="2B26CBD71B01AC9FC125792D004CF942" name="Facebook Application Development" startTime="2011-11-09T15:40:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="Facebook" />
						<tag name="JavaScript" />
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>Come learn how you can build Facebook applications using familiar tools and languages. We will discuss some common tasks and problems developers face when building Facebook apps such as authentication, scale, error handling, and high-availability. You will learn about the core components such as the Graph API, FQL, and XFBML. We will walk through different scenarios such as canvas apps, websites, and mobile apps and how the Facebook C# SDK and Facebook JS SDK makes building these apps easier.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="462C3A45DFB543EDC125792D004CAD7A" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="BCDB909C72A4B16EC1257920004CFA87" name="Kinect SDK for Windows - A new way to interface with applications" startTime="2011-11-09T16:45:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>With the Kinect SDK the Kinect is introduced in the PC world, and this time it goes way beyond gaming and ideas for Kinect use business and non-game applications are already plentiful. 
In this session we will look at a few of those ideas and look at some demos that will hopefully inspire you and jumpstart your Kinect development. Sure, we'll look at a bit of code, but mostly this will be an inspiration session and a discussion around what you should think about when designing for Kinect.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="9C39C7E00442C884C125791F0030A8C5" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="D1BB3B95BBD9016BC125792C0047F763" name="Web Performance Triage" startTime="2011-11-10T10:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>We all know the common tricks for improving perceived performance, but often far too little emphasis is given on making the servers do their work more efficiently - otherwise all you achieve by scaling-out is distributed slowness. Here we take a hands-on look at some pragmatic ways to measure and improve the performance of your server-side code. The examples focus on ASP.NET MVC, but the themes should apply to most .NET web development, and beyond.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="FED079F9EE605A14C125792C0047E24E" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="18876948EB9606C0C12578B000468EDB" name="NuGet In Depth: Empowering Open Source on the .NET Platform" startTime="2011-11-10T11:10:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="geek culture" />
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>NuGet makes the integration between your apps and 3rd party components easy as pie by providing a simple and extensible process. In this session we'll cover how you can create, consume and publish your libraries (packages) and fully leverage external components while at the same time contributing to the .NET OSS community.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="88DE8E0DC68D646CC12578B0004652C0" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="C0971DB052597D8FC125792E0044DE61" name="Making your Application Cloud-ready" startTime="2011-11-10T13:00:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name="AppHarbor" />
						<tag name="Architecture" />
						<tag name="Cloud Computing" />
						<tag name="Windows Azure" />
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>Do you have a feeling that the applications you write won't run and scale in the cloud? Standard development practices include many vices that make applications cloud-incompatible. Machines fail in the cloud and the local filesystem is not be trusted. A request may be served by any of a group of instances, so even caching session-data in memory is suspect. This session will show you how to take a web application and convert it into a stateless, cloud-ready and super-scalable monster.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="F1B68C41BED92867C12578BF005DC4A2" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="8CDEB3740BB9C647C125787F0069A505" name="Creating a Top 500 Internet Website in C# for Dummies" startTime="2011-11-10T14:05:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>Do you have what it takes to build a web-scale service? Is your puny web tier enterprisey enough to handle thousands of requests per second? You want the traffic? You can't handle the traffic! Jeff Atwood shares some key lessons in scaling and growing a large, public website on the .NET stack.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="068AF23FE90C8231C125787F006999E3" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="AA2B92C8F4A8847DC12578BD003884D6" name="Actor Model Programming in C#" startTime="2011-11-10T15:15:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>With multi-core processors in all desktop computers and nearly every mobile device, developers must use asynchronous operations and concurrency to create responsive applications. The Actor programming model is an increasingly popular method of achieving the scalability without the impact to productivity that is inherent using traditional concurrency approaches. Stact is a library that enables C# developers to leverage the power of Actors, bringing the simplified concurrent programming to .NET.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="CE4242DCD64AB619C12578BD003879C5" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
				<session id="D0B88CEB8C3924FAC125787F006A1934" name="Phone Apps Unlimited" startTime="2011-11-10T16:20:00" level="" videofile1="" videofile2="" length="50">
					<tags>
						<tag name=".NET" />
					</tags>
					<description>Writing apps for mobile devices can be reminiscent of coding 20 years ago; there are limited resources and often limited APIs. But unlike 20 years ago, we have access to unlimited resources through the internet. In this .NET-based talk, I’ll look at how to bridge that gap between phones or tablets and the Azure cloud, to store data, run “background” processes, and do things not permitted by phone APIs or the dreaded Terms Conditions.</description>
					<speakers>
						<speaker id="D26D0355769B55A0C125787F006A0895" />
					</speakers>
				</session>
			</sessions>
		</track>
	</tracks>
	<speakers>
		<speaker name="Aaron Parecki" id="1D58C1B897A2B6ACC12579080054F93D" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/1D58C1B897A2B6ACC12579080054F93D/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Geoloqi.com" title="">
			<biography>Aaron Parecki has been a GPS enthusiast since the age of six, when he first discovered the art of programming. Today he is a Portland-based iPhone and PHP developer interested in solving practical problems with technology. In his free time, he enjoys geolocation, linguistics, and building home automation systems and IRC bots with a sense of humor. For the past 2½ years, he has been tracking and visualizing his location at 6 second intervals. He created Geoloqi.com with Amber Case in an effort to help people connect in the real world. He has 11 years experience in web app development, database design, and server administration.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Alasdair Allan" id="0CE18D33C0D2E936C12578C3005BC6F5" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/0CE18D33C0D2E936C12578C3005BC6F5/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Babilim Light Industries" title="">
			<biography>Alasdair Allan is the author of Learning iPhone Programming and Programming iPhone Sensors published by O'Reilly Media. He is a senior research fellow at the University of Exeter working on machine learning and its applications in real time, real world, systems. He also runs a small technology consulting business writing bespoke software, building open hardware and providing training.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Alex Boisvert" id="F645E05E18923A44C12578CB0002AF1D" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/F645E05E18923A44C12578CB0002AF1D/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Bizo" title="">
			<biography>Alex is a software architect/engineer at Bizo and an open-source enthusiast. He is the creator of Stopwatch (Scala performance metrics library), co-creator of the JDBM project (Java embedded key-value store), maintainer of the Simplistic project (Scala SimpleDB bindings), committer and PMC Chair of Apache Buildr (Ruby-based build system for JVM languages, including Java, Scala, Groovy and Clojure) and currently working on his next project called &quot;Revolute&quot; -- a Scala-based query language for Apache Hadoop.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Alexander Tarnowski" id="54FE6EE9F0C514ADC12578AE007A39FF" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/54FE6EE9F0C514ADC12578AE007A39FF/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Crisp" title="">
			<biography>Alexander is a developer and architect with a decade of experience in the field and a broad perspective on software development, based on his work as a creator, maintainer, and reviewer of software. He has mostly worked with enterprise applications written in Java. 
Having worked in all phases of the development process, he believes in craftsmanship, quality, and technical excellence at every stage, which has naturally led him towards testing. He spends a lot of time thinking about what goes on around him and tries to spot patterns, practices, and habits. 
Recently, he has started sharing his findings through his blog, articles, and presentations.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Alexis Ohanian" id="0300E2CD832388D2C1257904006C9617" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/0300E2CD832388D2C1257904006C9617/$file/thumb.jpg" company="" title="">
			<biography>Reddit, co-founded by Alexis Ohanian and friend Steve Huffman, has become one of the World Wide Web's most striking examples of democracy in action. Founded in 2005, it grew a user base of tens of thousands and quickly attracted the attention of publisher Condé Nast, which acquired it in 2006. Unlike &quot;social bookmarking&quot; sites (such as Delicious), Reddit fashions itself a platform for &quot;social news,&quot; where the readers themselves control the front page by voting stories up above and down below the fold.
Ohanian left Reddit in his official capacity in 2009, but continues to be involved with the site's direction as a sort of godfather, dispensing friendly wisdom (and t-shirts) from his user account, kn0thing. Of late, he's focusing on Breadpig, a hub for geeky books and merchandise where all the profits are donated to charity (over $100,000 given away so far in just 2 years). In early 2010, he spent three months in Armenia as a Kiva Fellow.
He loves hummus.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Amber Case" id="3DDF11112996AA34C12578FE0078FCB1" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/3DDF11112996AA34C12578FE0078FCB1/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Geoloqi" title="">
			<biography>Amber Case is a cyborg anthropologist and user experience designer from Portland, Oregon. She has been featured in Forbes, WIRED, Time and many other publications, both in the United States and around the world. Her main focus is mobile software, augmented reality and data visualization, and reducing the amount of time and space it takes for people to connect. Case founded Geoloqi.com, a private location sharing application, out of a frustration with existing social protocols around text messaging and wayfinding.

Case has spoken at TED on technology and humans and was featured in Fast Company 2010 as one of the Most Influential Women in Technology. She’s worked with Fortune 500 companies at Wieden+Kennedy and on major applications at Vertigo Software. She is @caseorganic on Twitter.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Anders Janmyr" id="0D1833DC4B4121A3C125792C00350E81" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/0D1833DC4B4121A3C125792C00350E81/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Jayway" title="">
			<biography>Anders Janmyr is a developer since about twenty years. He loves writing
code but, also talking and writing about it.

He has worked in many different domains, from databases and servers to
mobile phones and robots, and has experience with small and large scale
architectures.

He has a wide experience of programming languages C, Smalltalk, Java, C#
Haskell, Lisp, Ruby and Javascript among others. The last years he has spent
mainly with Ruby and Javascript.

He loves the combination of dynamic languages and test-driven development since
it gives him a short feedback loop and peace of mind.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Andreas Öhlund" id="6DFEA68E544BA287C12578B800292F75" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/6DFEA68E544BA287C12578B800292F75/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Frontwalker" title="">
			<biography>Andreas Öhlund, one of the lead developers for NServiceBus, is an enterprise development expert with thorough experience from messaging based DDD and CQRS solutions. Andreas is a passionate developer, speaker and trainer, you can follow him on twitter using @andreasohlund</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Arun Gupta" id="99B910563CAB529BC12578AE002033A4" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/99B910563CAB529BC12578AE002033A4/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Oracle" title="">
			<biography>Arun Gupta is a Java evangelist working at Oracle. He works to create and foster the community around Java EE and GlassFish. He has extensive world wide speaking experience on myriad of topics and loves to engage with the community, customers, partners, and JUGs everywhere to spread the goodness of Java. He is a prolific blogger at http://blogs.oracle.com/arungupta with over 1200 blog entries and frequent visitors from all around the world with a cumulative page visits &gt; 1.2 million.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Aslak Ransby" id="F37E41500819E43BC125792E003F75E3" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/F37E41500819E43BC125792E003F75E3/$file/thumb.jpg" company="" title="">
			<biography>Aslak Ransby is an advocate for the free and open internet. Founding
member of the Danish digital rights think tank, Bitbureauet, and
studying for his masters in Social and Cultural IT, at the IT University
of Copenhagen.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Aslam Khan" id="A4EAE7D647C659F0C12578BF006374CE" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/A4EAE7D647C659F0C12578BF006374CE/$file/thumb.jpg" company="factor10" title="">
			<biography>Aslam Khan is a software architect at factor10 with more than 18 years experience. He has a particular passion for tackling complex problems and with the belief that simplicity is a choice that generates creativity. He is pragmatist that considers the only truthful implementation of an architecture is the code that gets executed. Aslam spends his time trying to be a better developer and helping others to do the same. You can read his blog at http://aslamkhan.net</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Carl Franklin" id="A66B776EE4F4D1E9C125792600406EB6" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/A66B776EE4F4D1E9C125792600406EB6/$file/thumb.jpg" company=".Net Rocks" title="">
			<biography>I started as a musician for fun, and a software developer for money. I started a hands-on training company in 1999 (www.franklins.net) which is still doing well to this day. In 2002 I started recording an hour-long talk show for .NET software developers and publishing it as an mp3 file. When podcasting became a &quot;thing&quot; in 2004 we jumped on that bandwagon. That show had 3.7 million downloads in 2006! In 2005 I started Pwop Productions (www.pwop.com) to bring our expertise in recording and producing online media into the market. We produce podcasts for Microsoft, Eastern Mountain Sports, Nintendo of America, Filemaker, Inc., Blackwell Publishing, and have other private relationships with Fortune 100 companies. 

Now I am finally going back to my first love, Music. I am producing bands and artists at Pwop Studios in New London, CT. Currently looking for more contacts in the music industry. 

I recorded, produced, and played on Ray Lamontagne's &quot;missing&quot; first album, One Lonesome Saddle, which turned into his demo for Trouble.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Charles Nutter" id="DF6984CDE5A1FE17C1257880003E9631" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/DF6984CDE5A1FE17C1257880003E9631/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Engine Yard" title="">
			<biography>Charles Oliver Nutter has been co-lead of the JRuby project for the past four years, working on performance and Java integration, and helping to coordinate community efforts. During that time JRuby has become a premier platform for Ruby users, allowing both a gateway to Java-centric organizations as well as an excellent Ruby implementation. Charles hopes to expand JRuby’s success to other JVM languages, building the JVM into the best platform for multi-language development.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Chris Patterson" id="CE4242DCD64AB619C12578BD003879C5" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/CE4242DCD64AB619C12578BD003879C5/$file/thumb.jpg" company="RelayHealth" title="">
			<biography>Chris is an architect for RelayHealth, the connectivity business of the leading healthcare services company in the US. There he is responsible for the architecture and development of applications and services that accelerate care delivery by connecting patients, providers, pharmacies, and financial institutions. As an open-source contributor, Chris is an author of MassTransit, a .NET service bus framework, and Topshelf, a Windows service framework.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Chris Thorpe" id="1EFBE15315022B1FC12578AF004418A2" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/1EFBE15315022B1FC12578AF004418A2/$file/thumb.jpg" company="" title="">
			<biography>Chris Thorpe works at Jaggeree, a consultancy that works on the intersection of content, data, people and play. We help people to define technologies and strategies that take full advantage of the emerging network society.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Christian Johansen" id="7D515E0384273415C1257888002496B1" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/7D515E0384273415C1257888002496B1/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Gitorious AS (gitorious.org gitorious.com)" title="">
			<biography>Originally a student in informatics, mathematics, and digital signal processing, Christian Johansen has spent his professional career specializing in web and front-end development with technologies such as JavaScript, CSS, and HTML using agile practices. Christian is a passionate programmer and TDD practitioner, and seizes every opportunity to enlighten others through courses, presentations and writing blog posts and a book.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Christian Lindegård Jepsen" id="D423BAB549E212FAC125792D00511324" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/D423BAB549E212FAC125792D00511324/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Sunstone Capital" title="">
			<biography>Christian brings a combination of international start-up, technology and media experience spanning more than 12 years in four countries. His background includes experience from founding start-ups, international fund raising, strategic operational planning, negotiations, and media strategy. Christian has founded three technology companies in the areas of web production, telecommunications, and digital TV. Two of these were Danish companies, while the third - Pangea - was founded in the US with an operational base in Europe. At Pangea, Christian was part of a team that raised approximately $450 million in debt and equity. Christian has lived and worked in Copenhagen, Washington DC, New York, Amsterdam and London.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Christian Panton" id="00DF42A089DAE7CBC12578A000479A73" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/00DF42A089DAE7CBC12578A000479A73/$file/thumb.jpg" company="" title="">
			<biography>Christian combines endless curiosity with software development. This has led him anywhere from setting up WiFi on the Greenland ice sheet to fiddling with the protocols of RFID tags.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Christian Weyer" id="DE7128AB58732BAFC1257926003F1B7F" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/DE7128AB58732BAFC1257926003F1B7F/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Thinktecture" title="">
			<biography>Christian Weyer is co-founder of solution architect at thinktecture, a company providing in-depth technical consulting and training services for software architects and developers. Christian has been focusing on the ideas and concepts of service-orientation and their practical translation in customer projects in the past years, with Windows Communication Foundation (WCF), Windows Workflow Foundation (WF) and Cloud Computing (with platforms like the Windows Azure platform) being the main areas and technologies applied recently. He tries to focus on the end-to-end aspects of distributed application architecture, design and implementation.

Christian's views on end-to-end architecture and distributed solutions are considered both mature and innovating. A number of customers have put confidence into his experience when it comes to apply .NET, WCF and WF to real problems and dealing with ideas like 'Software plus Services'. The national and international developer and architect community knows Christian from his weblog, webcasts, forums activities, user group talks and conference performances. He was selected as one of the Microsoft MVPs for Windows Azure [Architecture] and is an independent Microsoft Regional Director for Germany.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Christoffer Krämer" id="DB19F3CF5F9B06D4C1257899003F8563" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/DB19F3CF5F9B06D4C1257899003F8563/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Gigantoskop" title="">
			<biography>I teach, design games and write for hire. Teaching comes natural for me but games, game design and writing the fantastic is my passion. I design board games, card games and write material for role-playing games.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Colin Young" id="A864AFF977F4015BC1257925004A2841" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/A864AFF977F4015BC1257925004A2841/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Cloudbot" title="">
			<biography>Colin Young is co-founder of Cloudbot, which makes mobile apps for everyone that needs to simplify their cloud data -- everything from your contacts to your pictures to your real-world experiences. Cloudbot is a venture-funded startup whose backers include the Groupon co-founders and is based in Chicago, USA.

Before Cloudbot, Colin worked as an iPhone and web developer for several companies in the Chicago area. He studied Computer Science and Interactive Media at DePaul University, Chicago.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Corey Haines" id="33A9B170937DDE76C12578C900660087" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/33A9B170937DDE76C12578C900660087/$file/thumb.jpg" company="coreyhaines" title="">
			<biography>After 12 years of coding for money, Corey Haines said enough and went on a year-long, journeyman pair-programming tour. Traveling the world, pair-programming for room and board, he spent his time teaching, learning and just living as a knowledge-cross-pollinating, little, software craftsmanship bee. For the past three years, Corey has focused his attention on helping developers improve their fundamental software design skills through the use of focused-practice events, such as coderetreat. Lately, Corey has been shifting his attention to getting kids excited about programming through building games in Scratch.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Dan North" id="E032F082D5681850C12578C000742B1D" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/E032F082D5681850C12578C000742B1D/$file/thumb.jpg" company="" title="">
			<biography>Dan has been writing software for over 20 years, and was a principal consultant with technology consultancy ThoughtWorks. Now a recent transplant to Chicago, he spends his time helping teams become more effective at delivering software, and presents at conferences such as JAOO, Agile and OOPSLA on topics ranging from learning theory to behaviour-driven development. He has published articles in the Java Developers' Journal and Better Software, and for CIO newsletters and the DSDM consortium.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="David Evans" id="D379E52E40B16BF3C125786300774F86" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/D379E52E40B16BF3C125786300774F86/$file/thumb.jpg" company="ThinkAlike Consulting Ltd" title="">
			<biography>David Evans is an independent consultant and agile coach with over 22 years of IT experience. A thought-leader in the field of agile testing, he has trained and consulted on this topic for clients in the UK, Ireland, Sweden, Germany, Australia, South Africa and Singapore. A regular speaker at events and conferences across Europe, David has also had several papers published in IT journals. He currently lives and works in the UK.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Donald Farmer" id="98389B108A5E77C8C12578BD0048928C" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/98389B108A5E77C8C12578BD0048928C/$file/thumb.jpg" company="QlikTech" title="">
			<biography>Donald Farmer is the QlikView Product Advocate, working with customers and partners to establish QlikView as the leading solution for Business Discovery. Donald has over twenty years experience in analytics and data management. In that time he has worked as a consultant, in startups and as a leader of Microsoft’s BI product teams. He is a speaker at many international events on business intelligence, data integration and data management, blogger, and author of several books.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Emil Kvarnhammar" id="4026DF0B8DF6B13AC12578C3004C9AF5" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/4026DF0B8DF6B13AC12578C3004C9AF5/$file/thumb.jpg" company="" title="">
			<biography>Emil Kvarnhammar is specialized in mobile platforms, with focus on security and MDM (Mobile Device Management). He has been involved in the development of many different mobile products and hardware related software components. A recent example is as Lead Engineer for the development and optimization of PlayStation™ emulation in Xperia™ Play, at Sony Ericsson in Silicon Valley.

Today he is doing security analysis, vulnerability testing and development of mobile software at TrueSec. He also holds courses and seminars about secure application development and MDM.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Felix Geisendörfer" id="47717052A75DF501C12578A4005C7AF9" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/47717052A75DF501C12578A4005C7AF9/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Debuggable Limited" title="">
			<biography>Felix Geisendörfer is a node.js core developer and has experienced it's strength and shortcomings first-hand while building transloadit.com. When not event-looping, he loves unicycling and watching squirrels.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Frank Schuil" id="A67B9A0BDBE63DC1C12579230050D36F" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/A67B9A0BDBE63DC1C12579230050D36F/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Qubulus" title="">
			<biography>Frank has founded several companies in the location-based services area: IRL Connect, Verbeterdebuurt and Qubulus. He is focused on the practical use cases for new technologies and their long- and short-term implications for consumers and business. His latest venture Qubulus has developed a software-only indoor positioning solution that can both locate mobile devices horizontally (~3m accurate) and vertically (~1m).</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Fredrik Mörk" id="A75255F52203D121C12578B8002716D3" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/A75255F52203D121C12578B8002716D3/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Diversify" title="">
			<biography>Fredrik Mörk is a consultant with Diversify, Sweden, working mainly within in .NET area. His assignments often contains a mix of being a developer, architect and a mentor. He often works through all of the stack, from the user experience down to the backend. He is also passionate about sharing his knowledge within as well as outside of his team, and is a frequent contributor on stackoverflow.com.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Fredrik Olsson" id="C140CF631F81774DC12578AE002AF9D0" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/C140CF631F81774DC12578AE002AF9D0/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Jawway AB" title="">
			<biography>Fredrik is a senior mobile expert at Jayway in Sweden, with iOS and embedded Java environments as specialty, with experience from iOS and Android since the first betas. He has a long experience in software development for a wide range of domains, development environments, and execution environments. An experience based in the firm belief that a broad knowledge makes you and even better developer at the specific field you choose work in.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Gary Short" id="7D13AA6B3FB4DE0EC12578BD0033B1DC" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/7D13AA6B3FB4DE0EC12578BD0033B1DC/$file/thumb.jpg" company="DevExpress" title="">
			<biography>Gary Short has over 20 years of experience in software development and has been involved with such industry powerhouses as American Express and IBM. Currently with Developer Express, Gary works alongside the frameworks division as their Technical Evangelist. He has a deep interest in technical architecture, focusing particularly on how architectural design can affect the delivery of development solutions. Gary’s core areas of interest are in technical debt and refactoring. Gary has been recognised as a Microsoft MVP for four consecutive years, and gives back to the developer community through his involvement with both community events, and national and international conferences throughout the UK, Europe and the United States.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Gojko Adzic" id="A6132D1B068B2536C125788E00688E8E" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/A6132D1B068B2536C125788E00688E8E/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Neuri Ltd" title="">
			<biography>Gojko Adzic is a consultant based in the UK who helps ambitious teams
worldwide implement Specification by Example and agile testing practices</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Greg Young" id="53988259A9936183C125787F006B2920" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/53988259A9936183C125787F006B2920/$file/thumb.jpg" company="" title="">
			<biography>Greg Young is an independent consultant who lives in two suitcases (literally). When not travelling around working for clients throughout the world you can often find him on the domain driven design list, blogging at codebetter.com, or floating upside down in a kayak through rapids.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Heather Willems and Nora Herting" id="21AC75F874D6361AC12578D1002EAF4B" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/21AC75F874D6361AC12578D1002EAF4B/$file/thumb.jpg" company="ImageThink" title="">
			<biography>Heather Willems and Nora Herting are co-founders of ImageThink, a graphic recording firm.

By transforming ideas into powerful visuals, ImageThink increases engagement, retention, and creativity for participants in meetings of all kinds. Imagethink supports strategy workshops, innovation sessions, and brainstorms in industries as different as healthcare to aerospace.

Both have backgrounds as educators. Nora taught both at The Ohio State University and Denison University. Heather taught at Minnesota Center for Photography, Minneapolis College of Art and Design, and The Ohio State University.

When not graphic recording, Nora can be found making fine art photography, while Heather focuses on illustrations that use text as image. As fine artists, they have exhibited their work individually throughout the United States.

Heather and Nora live in Brooklyn, NY and travel to work around the country.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Heiko Seeberger" id="7064422D70BBE62EC12578C4004E92DB" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/7064422D70BBE62EC12578C4004E92DB/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Typesafe" title="">
			<biography>Heiko Seeberger is the Director Professional Services at Typesafe. He has been a Scala enthusiast ever since he came to know this beautiful language in 2008. He has more than ten years of professional expertise in consulting and software development on the Java platform, actively contributes to Scala community projects and regularly shares his expertise in articles and talks.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Henrik Andersson" id="7645723878860845C12578AE00312BB3" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/7645723878860845C12578AE00312BB3/$file/thumb.jpg" company="House of Test" title="">
			<biography>Henrik Andersson is consultant and founder of House of Test, consultancy and outsourcing based in Sweden and China. He helps companies increase their efficiency and reconstructing their testing. He provides leadership and consulting for managers and leads. He tests, coaches, consults, speaks, writes, manages and thinks about software testing and problem solving.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Ian Robinson" id="E3481D6B24F01B54C12578C60011A748" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/E3481D6B24F01B54C12578C60011A748/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Neo Technology" title="">
			<biography>Ian Robinson is Director of Customer Success for Neo Technology, the company behind Neo4j, the world's leading open source graph database. He is a co-author of 'REST in Practice' (O'Reilly) and a contributor to the forthcoming books 'REST: From Research to Practice' (Springer) and 'Service Design Patterns' (Addison-Wesley). He presents at conferences worldwide on the big Web graph of REST, and the awesome graph capabilities of Neo4j, and blogs at http://iansrobinson.com.


</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Ilya Grigorik" id="482EA8E9642F26E7C12578CC0023E5B5" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/482EA8E9642F26E7C12578CC0023E5B5/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Google" title="">
			<biography>Ilya Grigorik is a developer, an open-source and Ruby evangelist, a data-geek, and a proverbial early adopter of all things digital. Now living in the San Francisco Bay Area, Ilya is working on Social Analytics @ Google. Prior to joining the Google Analytics team, Ilya was the founder and CTO of PostRank, a social web analytics company which was acquired by Google in June 2011. In 2008, Ilya was the recipient of the Ruby Hero award for his contributions to the Ruby community.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Jack Nutting" id="3B4C30B59413441AC12578AE002A8235" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/3B4C30B59413441AC12578AE002A8235/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Toca Boca" title="">
			<biography>Jack Nutting has been using Cocoa since the olden days, long before it was even called Cocoa. He's used Cocoa and its predecessors to develop software for a wide range of industries and applications including gaming, graphic design, online digital distribution, telecommunications, finance, publishing, and travel. When he's not working on Mac, iPhone, or iPad projects, he's developing web applications with Ruby on Rails. Jack is a passionate proponent of Objective-C and the Cocoa frameworks.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Janet Gregory" id="889EB8F85EA67F96C125785A0009AE65" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/889EB8F85EA67F96C125785A0009AE65/$file/thumb.jpg" company="DragonFire Inc." title="">
			<biography>An agile testing coach and practitioner, Janet Gregory is the co-author of Agile Testing: A Practical Guide for Testers and Agile Teams and a contributor to 97 Things Every Programmer Should Know. Janet specializes in showing agile teams how testers can add value in areas beyond critiquing the product; for example, by guiding development with business-facing tests. For the past ten years, Janet has been working with teams to transition to agile development, and teaches agile testing courses and tutorials worldwide. Janet contributes articles to publications such as Software Test Performance Magazine and Agile Journal, and enjoys sharing her experiences at conferences and user group meetings around the world. Janet was named one of the 13 Women of Influence in testing by Software Test Performance magazine.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Janne Elvelid" id="0AD72E244BB037A8C125788F0056E02A" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/0AD72E244BB037A8C125788F0056E02A/$file/thumb.jpg" company=".SE (The Internetinfrastructure Foundation)" title="">
			<biography>Janne is currently running the project &quot;Svenskarna och Internet&quot;, the biggest usersruvey in Sweden about Internet, also a part of the World Internet Project, one of the biggest Internet reserarch projects in the world. He's also managing the conference &quot;Internetdagarna&quot; and responsible for Internetstatistics at .SE. Previously managing director at World Internet Institute.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Jean Tabaka" id="7B7DD621EB77B08DC12578AB007D28BE" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/7B7DD621EB77B08DC12578AB007D28BE/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Rally Software" title="">
			<biography>Jean Tabaka, Agile Fellow with Rally Software, is continuing to learn about software development principles, processes, and practices. She seeks humane approaches that deliver high value in our business communities. Her work in product development flow reaches beyond traditional Agile. She also works in systems thinking and complexity theory. Jean holds a Masters in Computer Science from Johns Hopkins University and is the author of “Collaboration Explained” and other articles on Agile organizations. Jean blogs at www.rallydev.com/agileblog and tweets as @jeantabaka.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Jeff Atwood" id="068AF23FE90C8231C125787F006999E3" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/068AF23FE90C8231C125787F006999E3/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Stack Exchange" title="">
			<biography>I was weaned as a software developer on various implementations of Microsoft's BASIC in the 80's, starting with my first microcomputer, the Texas Instruments TI-99/4a. I continued on the PC with Visual Basic 3.0 and Windows 3.1 in the early 90's, although I also spent significant time writing Pascal code in the first versions of Delphi. I am now quite comfortable in VB.NET or C#, despite the evils of case sensitivity. I currently work full time on my blog while building stackoverflow.com.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Jeff Patton" id="0F5612DF26331F1AC12578640020C3F0" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/0F5612DF26331F1AC12578640020C3F0/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Jeff Patton Associates" title="">
			<biography>Jeff makes use of over 15 years experience with a wide variety of products from on-line aircraft parts ordering to electronic medical records to help organizations improve the way they work. Where many development processes focus on delivery speed and efficiency, Jeff balances those concerns with the need for building products that deliver exceptional value and marketplace success.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Jim Benson" id="E8196EA0CF5974EFC1257864002027A7" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/E8196EA0CF5974EFC1257864002027A7/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Modus Cooperandi" title="">
			<biography>Jim Benson incorporates his background in cognitive psychology, government, and management to build community through policy, technology, and collaboration. His management consultancy Modus Cooperandi helps organizations change and develop sustainable teams through the application of lean principles, agile methodologies, and social media.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Jim Webber" id="5E26A118C9856B49C12578C7004C4C05" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/5E26A118C9856B49C12578C7004C4C05/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Neo Technology" title="">
			<biography>Dr. Jim Webber is Chief Scientist with Neo Technology the company behind the popular open source graph database Neo4j, where he works on graph database server technology and writes open source software.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Jimmy Nilsson" id="99D83AB23621359EC12578800042A6CB" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/99D83AB23621359EC12578800042A6CB/$file/thumb.jpg" company="factor10" title="">
			<biography>Jimmy Nilsson is co-founder and CEO of factor10. He has written two books (Applying Domain-Driven Design and Patterns [ADDDP] and .NET Enterprise Design [NED]). He has also been training and speaking at conferences (like OOPSLA, JAOO, Öredev), but above everything else, he is a developer with almost twenty years of experience.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Johan Lindfors" id="D4F59D75FC378DBFC125792700271A06" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/D4F59D75FC378DBFC125792700271A06/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Coderox" title="">
			<biography>Johan Lindfors has been working with Windows Phone since the early days of Windows Mobile and are often speaking about the platform at various events. Johan has founded the company Coderox, currently entirely focused on Windows Phone 7 with various customers and engagements, some leveraging Silverlight and others using XNA. Before Coderox, he worked at Microsoft for almost 13 years, and have also been the head of development at Infozone.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Johanna Rothman" id="B6D0D391E1E2B1FEC1257864006A9A59" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/B6D0D391E1E2B1FEC1257864006A9A59/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Rothman Consulting Group, Inc" title="">
			<biography>Johanna Rothman works with companies to improve how they manage their product development--to maximize management and technical staff productivity and to improve product quality. Johanna is a leader in the Agile community, having most recently chaired the Agile2009 conference. Johanna is the author of several books:
-	Manage Your Project Portfolio: Increase Your Capacity and Finish More Projects
-	The 2008 Jolt Productivity award-winning Manage It! Your Guide to Modern, Pragmatic Project Management
-	Behind Closed Doors: Secrets of Great Management
-	Hiring the Best Knowledge Workers, Techies Nerds: The Secrets and Science of Hiring Technical People
She writes columns for Stickyminds.com and on “extreme project management” for Gantthead.com, and writes two blogs on her web site, jrothman.com. She is a host of the Amplifying Your Effectiveness conference. 
</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Jon Dahl" id="76A43012DA9334E1C12578B9005E7936" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/76A43012DA9334E1C12578B9005E7936/$file/thumb.jpg" company="" title="">
			<biography>Jonathan is co-founder of Zencoder, a Y Combinator-backed startup that provides awesome video encoding as a service in the cloud. Before Zencoder, ran a Ruby on Rails development shop, blogged at http://railspikes.com, wrote a Master's thesis on philosophy and theology, and tried (unsuccessfully) to become a Lisp hacker.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Jon Skeet" id="9428A6E3C0EADE3BC12578B7006B4D2F" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/9428A6E3C0EADE3BC12578B7006B4D2F/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Google" title="">
			<biography>Jon is a software engineer working in the Mobile team at Google. While his day job primarily involves Java code, Jon is a huge C# enthusiast. His book on the language, “C# in Depth” is now in its second edition. He is probably best known for his contributions to Stack Overflow, the developer QA web site – although before Stack Overflow he was a prolific newsgroup poster. Although Jon is employed by Google, his talks are his personal opinions; he is not speaking on behalf of Google.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Jonas Jacobi" id="043666AE7B2C4F08C12578B5005BB2A9" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/043666AE7B2C4F08C12578B5005BB2A9/$file/thumb.jpg" company="KAAZING" title="">
			<biography>Jonas is co-founder and chief executive zinger of Kaazing Corporation. Before co-founding Kaazing Jonas worked as VP of Product Management responsible for the product management and marketing strategy for Brane Corporation, a startup company in Silicon Valley. A native of Sweden, Jonas has worked in the software industry for more than eighteen years. Prior to his appointment as vice president for Brane, he worked 8 years for Oracle as a Java EE and open source Evangelist, and product manager responsible for the product management of products and technologies such as JavaServer Faces, Oracle ADF Faces, and Oracle ADF Faces Rich Client in the Oracle JDeveloper team.

His passion is software evolution and how we constantly are able to reset expectations on what is possible. He is a frequent speaker at and has written numerous articles for leading IT magazines such as Java Developer's Journal, JavaPro, AjaxWorld, and Oracle Magazine. Jonas is co-author of the book Pro JSF and Ajax: Building Rich Internet Components, (Apress).</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Joonas Lehtinen" id="77D0C918FC118601C12578AE0020ADB4" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/77D0C918FC118601C12578AE0020ADB4/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Vaadin Ltd." title="">
			<biography>Dr. Joonas Lehtinen is one of the core developers of Vaadin, a Java-based framework for building business-oriented Rich Internet Applications. Joonas has been developing applications for the web since 1995 with a strong focus on Ajax and Java. He is the founder and CEO of the company behind the Vaadin framework and is a frequent speaker at international conferences.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Jörgen Larsson" id="A58974023A9DA684C125788F003DF160" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/A58974023A9DA684C125788F003DF160/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Sociologiska inst. / Tidsverkstanden ek. för." title="">
			<biography>Current position
- Department of Sociology, Universtity of Gothenburg. 

Past positions
- Project leader in public health projects at Tidsverkstaden ek. för. 
- Consultant in environmental management at Dynamo Ecology
- Political secretary for the city council in Gothenburg (50%)
- Consultant in environmental economics at EkoEko miljökonsult AB

Education and degrees
- Doctoral studies in Sociology
- Bachelor degree in business administration at the School of Economics in Gothenburg
</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Kim Hindart" id="957174DC42E095DCC12578CB0024044D" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/957174DC42E095DCC12578CB0024044D/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Hindart Consulting" title="">
			<biography>Lives in Uppsala and works as a Solutions Designer specializing in mobile solutions. Kim has been developing applications for Enterprises since 1998, with a background in the military and the media industry. He has made large mobile deployments on BlackBerry, Android and iOS alike. He is currently consulted by the insurance industry to assess and investigate IT-related damages and has first hand experience from &quot;when things go wrong&quot;</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Klas Skogmar" id="0940243B1CD9D40AC12578C5006981DA" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/0940243B1CD9D40AC12578C5006981DA/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Arkatay Consulting AB" title="">
			<biography>Klas is a PMP certified project manager and management consultant with an extensive background in both software and business development. He regularly holds courses and seminars in both agile development and other areas, such as PMBOK and ITIL. Klas has worked as a project manager, teacher, coach, mentor, deployment manager, problem manager and developer. He is also an entrepreneur with experience from founding and managing companies in various industries over the years.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Luca Minudel" id="D8F29D3222E036ECC12578B600368BB9" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/D8F29D3222E036ECC12578B600368BB9/$file/thumb.jpg" company="" title="">
			<biography>Extreme Programmer and Lean-Agile Coach, experienced in Scrum, XP and Lean-Agile. Has worked with large and legacy code-bases, complex domains, enterprise level applications.

Working in professional software development since 1989. With Agile practices since 2002.

During 2006-2009 has contributed to advance the adoption of Agile practices in a leading F1 Racing Team. In a unique context characterized by high levels of pressure, uncertainty, interdependency and rapid unpredictable changes.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Majk Jakobsen" id="36B93A9D0E00ACE6C12578A0003F23E6" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/36B93A9D0E00ACE6C12578A0003F23E6/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Independent" title="">
			<biography>Majk is Director of Photography on several of Cinemantrix films and commercials including An Affair with Dolls and Another Pea, Another Day.Majk is one of Cinemantrix cinematographers. Majk graduated from Skurups Film School in Sweden in 2004 and has since worked as a cinematographer and first assistant cameraman.Majk has worked with everything from commercials, short films and music videos to television shows.
One of the films where Majk was Director of Photography was &quot;Peace Talk&quot; which was the only Swedish film at the Sundance Film Festival in 2007.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Marc Gravell" id="FED079F9EE605A14C125792C0047E24E" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/FED079F9EE605A14C125792C0047E24E/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Stack Exchange" title="">
			<biography>Marc is part of the development team for Stack Exchange (and a self-confessed Stack Overflow junkie), and has been a C# MVP for the last 4 years. He has a long history of open source projects, and tries to focus on high-performance, low-impact libraries (hiding all the &quot;ugly&quot; from app developers). Before his transition to Stack Exchange, his history is coprorate / line-of-business (mainly on the Microsoft / .NET stack).</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Marc Mercuri" id="7E1C126299BC6BFFC12578B8006454D1" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/7E1C126299BC6BFFC12578B8006454D1/$file/thumb.jpg" company="" title="">
			<biography>Marc is a Sr. Director in the Cloud Strategy team, where he leads a team of geo-distributed architects that engage on strategic Azure and hybrid cloud projects. This team engaged with 50 customers worldwide this year, with lessons learned and best practices captured in whitepapers, presentations, and videos for use by the Microsoft field and partners. Prior to joining that team, Marc served in senior architecture and strategy roles in Microsoft HQ, where he led high visibility projects in areas related to robotics, cloud, mobile, social, search, and crowdsourcing.
 
Marc has been actively working in the software and services industry for the past 18 years and has worked on ground in Europe, Latin America, and the United States on a number of projects and products. In his career, Marc has served as an architect in lead roles that have spanned startups, enterprises, and ISVs across multiple verticals. Marc is the author of four books and has 27 patents pending in the areas of cloud, mobile, and social.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Marcus Johnson" id="78873E08DEBFAE1EC1257933007B216F" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/78873E08DEBFAE1EC1257933007B216F/$file/thumb.jpg" company="&lt;Symbio&gt;" title="">
			<biography>Marcus is a seasoned system architect, building measurement and control systems for more than a decade. His mission is to bring software industry best practices into the world of industrial and scientific systems, predominately graphically designed. After years of presenting and training, the tables have turned and Marcus is now also a G-Evangelist, presenting the experience of graphically designing advanced real-time systems and FPGAs to the traditional software engineering industry.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Marianne Larsson" id="0CF3F2D2060EF4BFC12579250040A854" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/0CF3F2D2060EF4BFC12579250040A854/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Teknopol and Mobile Heights" title="">
			<biography>I work as a Business Advisor but am also the Director of Mobile Heights Business Center (MHBC). My background includes an engineering degree and 15 years’ experience from high-level marketing and product and business development in international industrial companies. I have also worked as a management consultant and run change and development projects in a wide range of organisations and companies.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Mark Rendle" id="D26D0355769B55A0C125787F006A0895" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/D26D0355769B55A0C125787F006A0895/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Dot Net Solutions" title="">
			<biography>Mark’s career in software design and development spans three decades and more programming languages than he cares to remember. He is currently employed as Principal Architect at Dot Net Solutions, creating software with ASP.NET MVC, WPF, Silverlight and Windows Azure. He is a Windows Azure MVP. In his spare time, he enjoys learning new programming languages and paradigms (2011 is the year of CoffeeScript and F#), and works on the Simple.Data project, and Pocket C# for Windows Phone 7.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Martin Gunnarsson" id="096D1F3F24880999C12578C40048B059" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/096D1F3F24880999C12578C40048B059/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Epsilon Information Technology" title="">
			<biography>Great programmers are usually lousy designers, and vice versa, but Martin is one of those rare crossbreeds who can handle both. Graphics programming and GUI design suits him particularly well, but being a true perfectionist, heʼs rarely satisfied with the results of his own work. Martin has worked with many different client side frameworks the last few years, including Swing, JavaFX, Android, Javascript and iOS.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Martin Jul" id="E86251FB36CCC6FDC125793B0080A562" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/E86251FB36CCC6FDC125793B0080A562/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Ative" title="">
			<biography>Martin Jul is a software developer in Copenhagen, Denmark.

A programmer since age 11 and a Clojure developer since 2009, he started the Copenhagen Clojure meet-ups to provide a forum for the Danish Clojure community to share their ideas. He also wrote the Docjure library to provide Excel spreadsheet manipulation in Clojure code small enough to tweet.

Over the years he has written software for a number of industries as diverse as military command-and-control systems and dating systems for teletext and SMS. He is currently working with the financial sector building trading systems in C# and Clojure.

He lives in Copenhagen, Denmark and is a partner in Ative.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Matthew J. McCullough" id="542D5DF563711C81C12578CE0023CB5C" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/542D5DF563711C81C12578CE0023CB5C/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Ambient Ideas, LLC" title="">
			<biography>Matthew McCullough is an energetic 14 year veteran of enterprise software development, open source education, and co-founder of Ambient Ideas, LLC, a Denver consultancy. Matthew currently is a member of the JCP, author of the Git Master Class and author of Building and Testing with Gradle for technology publisher O'Reilly. He channels his teaching energy through activities as President of the Denver Open Source Users Group.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Mattias Karlsson" id="0C260088D8D00CB2C12579170027B27F" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/0C260088D8D00CB2C12579170027B27F/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Avega Group" title="">
			<biography>Mattias spends most of his time working with software development in the financial sector as well as leading a Java User Group in Stockholm. Mattias has worked with software development since 1993. Through the years he has gained experience from many different roles, including developer, architect, team leader, coach, manager, and teacher. Mattias also contributed to the book &quot;97 Things Every Programmer Should Know&quot; and is awarded Java Champion status.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Michael Möller" id="C96AE9642B9D782AC12578AE004F7BE9" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/C96AE9642B9D782AC12578AE004F7BE9/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Labitat" title="">
			<biography>Michael Möller has been in computers about four decades. He's been in everything related to building and running software systems as Programmer, Principal Senior System Design Engineer, Project Manager, and Quality Assurance Manager, doing work in USA, England and Denmark. Currently employed in Miracle A/S, Denmark with database (Oracle) consultancy and education.

For the last year Michael has been active in Labitat, a Hackerspace in Copenhagen, the inspiration and source of the RepRap session.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Michael Nygard" id="5252E2BD2AAE735BC125786400213B84" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/5252E2BD2AAE735BC125786400213B84/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Relevance, Inc." title="">
			<biography>Michael's desire to teach what he knows shows in daily work, speaking engagements, and writing. Michael wrote &quot;Release It!&quot;---about building large scale systems to survive the real world, rather than just passing QA---and has contributed to several other books. These days, he is devoted to improving the odds that a client's system will make money for them, by understanding time, uncertainty, risk, ignorance, and architecture.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Nathan Totten" id="462C3A45DFB543EDC125792D004CAD7A" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/462C3A45DFB543EDC125792D004CAD7A/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Microsoft" title="">
			<biography>Nathan Totten is a Technical Evangelist at Microsoft, he is also the creator and lead developer of the Facebook C# SDK. Before Microsoft, Nathan was a Senior Software Engineer at Thuzi where he worked on social media applications and analytics tools. He has experience building Windows Azure applications that handle large traffic spikes and maintain high availability and performance. He is also actively involved in open source development and the developer community.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Neal Ford" id="1B7778A85BC08E6CC12578D100576D07" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/1B7778A85BC08E6CC12578D100576D07/$file/thumb.jpg" company="ThoughtWorks" title="">
			<biography>Neal Ford is Software Architect and Meme Wrangler at ThoughtWorks, a global IT consultancy with an exclusive focus on end-to-end software development and delivery. He is also the designer and developer of applications, magazine articles, presentations, and author and/or editor of 6 books spanning a variety of technologies, including the most recent The Productive Programmer</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Nick Harris" id="2A202A7C54362AC0C12578C00065ECC5" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/2A202A7C54362AC0C12578C00065ECC5/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Microsoft" title="">
			<biography>Nick Harris is a Technical Evangelist at Microsoft specializing in Windows Azure. Before Microsoft, he founded AdGAC - a mobile advertising company developed using Windows Azure, WP7 and ASP.NET MVC. In the 9 years prior, Nick worked as both a consultant and Senior Software Engineer delivering smart client apps, distributed enterprise apps and airborne software systems. While not working you can find him blogging about Windows Azure along with a diverse range of other related content.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Oliver Gierke" id="CC0D20783930E1DEC12578F8004D5FEB" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/CC0D20783930E1DEC12578F8004D5FEB/$file/thumb.jpg" company="" title="">
			<biography>Oliver Gierke is engineer at SpringSource, a division of VMware, project lead of the Spring Data JPA module and involved into other Spring Data modules (e.g. MongoDB) as well. He has been into developing enterprise applications and open source projects for over 6 years now. His working focus is centered around software architecture, Spring and persistence technologies. He is regularly speaking at German and international conferences as well as author of technology articles.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Pat Kua" id="770A27AE50FC60D7C1257880001E855E" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/770A27AE50FC60D7C1257880001E855E/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Thoughtworks" title="">
			<biography>Patrick Kua works as an active, generalising specialist for ThoughtWorks and dislikes being put into a box. Patrick is often found leading technical teams, frequently coaching people and organisations in lean and agile methods, and sometimes facilitating situations beyond adversity. Patrick is fascinated by elements of learning and continuous improvement always helping others to develop enthusiasm for these same elements.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Per-Olof Hedvall" id="8A7B0A92BF53F35EC12579300036FA16" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/8A7B0A92BF53F35EC12579300036FA16/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Lund University" title="">
			<biography>Per-Olof Hedvall is a researcher in Rehabilitation Engineering and Design at the Department of Design Sciences at Lund University, where he leads the research group CERTEC. His research deals with accessibility and participation. He is particularly interested in new interactive communication media and new forms of augmentative and alternative communication that enable the interaction between children with disabilities and their families. He has also worked extensively on how commercial computer games can be adapted so that people with disabilities can also play them.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Peter Neubauer" id="4200BFDFA1686EECC12579250078A115" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/4200BFDFA1686EECC12579250078A115/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Neo Technology" title="">
			<biography>Peter has been a founding member of several Open Source Efforts like www.neo4j.org, www.ops4j.org and www.qi4j.org.

Right now, Peter is focusing on turning Open Source Projects into profitable companies. Also, Peter is helping technology and mobile startups and organizing events like ThoughtMade and TEDx Öresund.

If you want brainstorming, feed him a Latte and you are in business :)</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Phil Haack" id="88DE8E0DC68D646CC12578B0004652C0" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/88DE8E0DC68D646CC12578B0004652C0/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Microsoft" title="">
			<biography>Phil Haack works for Microsoft as a Senior Program Manager on the Web Platform and Tools team aiming to build great products for developers. While he delves in many areas of ASP.NET, his primary projects are ASP.NET MVC and NuGet Package Manager, both released under an OSS license. In his spare time, he writes about software on his blog, http://haacked.com/ and works on the Subtext open source blog engine.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Portia Tung" id="BBE4591C8578285BC12578B50077706E" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/BBE4591C8578285BC12578B50077706E/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Independent" title="">
			<biography>Portia specialises in Agile adoption and organisational change as a Consultant-Coach. She's passionate about realising and increasing human potential through Systems Thinking, Real Options and team collaboration. She strives to build effective and meaningful teams by pragmatically applying Lean and Agile Values, Principles and Practices.

She's had a number of roles over the years, ranging from Java developer, to development manager, consultant-coach and faciliator.

Portia's the creator of Agile Fairytales (www.agilefairytales.org), a series of learning games that help adults rediscover the lessons we learned as children but have since forgotten. She's passionate about inventing and playing games because she believes we can all improve continuously through play to achieve our dreams.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Pradeep Soundararajan" id="B1462034B67D0A0AC12578CC0027F4AF" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/B1462034B67D0A0AC12578CC0027F4AF/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Moolya Software Testing Private Limited" title="">
			<biography>Pradeep is an awarded thought leader, renowned author, invited writer and speaker around the world. He co-founded Moolya Software Testing Private Limited ( www.moolya.com ) which is headquartered in Bangalore, India and is a new generation testing services company. 

His consulting stories, test reports and experience reports have fascinated many people across the world. He has consulted for product startups, small medium size software organizations, and multi billion dollar organizations. Pradeep's Tester Tested! blog http://testertested.blogspot.com is one of the widely influential read blogs in the industry.

He likes to mention that in past he was fired from a large organization as they considered him as the worst tester they ever hired. He was finding bugs and they couldn't show 98% test case pass to the senior management. He is humorous and there have been very few people who have not laughed to his humor :-P</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Pär Sikö" id="E0DADC8949FC97DFC12578C400266558" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/E0DADC8949FC97DFC12578C400266558/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Jayway" title="">
			<biography>Pär is a passionate developer whoʼs been working with client side Java for more than ten years and that is hoping for another ten years filled with challenges and new technology. Pär is a fast learner with a need to always learn more and never being satisfied, always wanting more. This is a good thing since GUI programming always ends up on pixel level where the details are of utter most importance.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Richard Campbell" id="AC217FE86663C99BC1257926003FB37B" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/AC217FE86663C99BC1257926003FB37B/$file/thumb.jpg" company=".Net Rocks" title="">
			<biography>Richard Campbell is one of the co-founders of Strangeloop Networks and today serves as product evangelist, introducing the company's unique story to advisors, investors, patent attorneys, beta-customer candidates, potential employees, etc. Richard has more than 30 years of high-tech experience and is both a Microsoft Regional Director and Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP). He has consulted with a number of leading North American organizations; BarnesNoble.com, Dow Chemical, Johnson Johnson Health Care Services, Reuters, Subaru/Isuzu and the U.S. Air Force. In addition to speaking at conferences around the world, Richard is co-host of the &quot;.NET Rocks!, the Internet Audio Talk Show for .NET Developers&quot; (www.dotnetrocks.com) podcast and the host of &quot;RunAs Radio, the Internet Audio Talk Show for IT Professionals&quot; (www.runasradio.com)</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Rickard Öberg" id="528D0D5817167F81C12578AE001F8E32" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/528D0D5817167F81C12578AE001F8E32/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Neo Technology" title="">
			<biography>Rickard has worked on several OpenSource projects that involve J2EE development, such as JBoss, XDoclet and WebWork. He has also been the principal architect of the SiteVision CMS/portal platform, where he used AOP as the foundation. Now he works for Jayway, and is interested in how to develop domain-oriented software that is well adapted for the new wave of Internet-centered applications.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Rikard Edgren" id="466FF005B0C0B40AC125790D006793F5" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/466FF005B0C0B40AC125790D006793F5/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Qamcom Karlstad" title="">
			<biography>Rikard Edgren, humanistic tester since 1998, specialized in generalities like test analysis and exploratory testing. Member of the think-tank The Test Eye. Co-author of &lt;a href=&quot;http://thetesteye.com/posters/TheTestEye_SoftwareQualityCharacteristics.pdf&quot;&gt;Software Quality Characteristics&lt;/a&gt;, author of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thetesteye.com/papers/TheLittleBlackBookOnTestDesign.pdf&quot;&gt;The Little Black Book on Test Design&lt;/a&gt;.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Robby Ingebretsen" id="FBEA087794522C56C125788000519436" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/FBEA087794522C56C125788000519436/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Think pixel lab" title="">
			<biography>Robby Ingebretsen is a user experience designer and developer with a singular purpose: making great ideas real. As founder and principal of Pixel Lab, Robby helps clients make stuff -- especially the sort of stuff that gets made from the unique full-bodied blend of a little design love and little engineering kung-fu.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Seb Lee-Delisle" id="6038141F4C3D476BC1257880004BF72F" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/6038141F4C3D476BC1257880004BF72F/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Plug-in Media" title="">
			<biography>Seb Lee-Delisle is an internationally recognised creative coder specialising in large scale installations. Whether building digital interactive fireworks displays or glow-stick voting systems, his work uses technology to bring people together in fun and exciting ways. He also produces creative visual effects for websites, games and apps in many programming languages and platforms.

He loves sharing the creativity of code with artists and programmers alike using physics, motion detection, 3D and particle systems. His work has pushed the boundaries of what is possible both on and off the web, and won two BAFTAs with Plug-in Media, the agency he co-founded in 2004.

A highly sought-after speaker, his recent Creative JavaScript / HTML5 workshop series sold out within hours. He co-hosts the Creative Coding Podcast, his blog can be found at seb.ly and he tweets @seb_ly.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Sebastien Lambla" id="2DA76E8016569F70C12578BD0039914B" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/2DA76E8016569F70C12578BD0039914B/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Caffeine IT" title="">
			<biography>Sebastien Lambla runs Caffeine IT, a .net consultancy / contracting company helping the good people of London adopt new technologies, new processes, new methodologies and in general anything that's new and shiny. Specializing in cutting-edge tools, from REST architectures to occasionally connected rich clients, Sebastien has been developing with .net since 2000, and has a secret love affair with javascript. In his spare time he’s working on OpenRasta, a resource-oriented MVC framework for .NET.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Selena Delesie" id="353467906EBCF349C12578A4000D8D92" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/353467906EBCF349C12578A4000D8D92/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Delesie Solutions Inc." title="">
			<biography>A consulting software tester and agile coach, Selena Delesie has been managing and coaching on software, testing, and agile practices for a decade. She facilitates the evolution of good teams and organizations into great ones using individualized and team-based coaching and interactive training experiences. Selena is a contributing author to How to Reduce the Cost of Software Testing and an active speaker, participant, and leader in numerous associations and conferences. Follow Selena online at DelesieSolutions.com.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Shmuel Gershon" id="C0B2C00315F18E98C125785B00652857" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/C0B2C00315F18E98C125785B00652857/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Intel Corp" title="">
			<biography>A technical leader at Intel Corporation, Shmuel Gershon has experience in firmware and software testing, and also in coaching testers and helping friends. His experience includes working in companies and as freelancer in different countries. He used to be a programmer, but discovered that testing is twice the fun. A frequent presenter at local software conferences, Shmuel is convinced that a most significant factor in our quest for quality is people, not features or technology. He blogs about software testing and is author of “Rapid Reporter”, an exploratory testing note taking tool.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Simon Peyton Jones" id="2953F952AD4E36A5C12578570058BC9B" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/2953F952AD4E36A5C12578570058BC9B/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Microsoft Research" title="">
			<biography>Simon Peyton Jones, MA, MBCS, CEng, graduated from Trinity College Cambridge in 1980. After two years in industry, he spent seven years as a lecturer at University College London, and nine years as a professor at Glasgow University, before moving to Microsoft Research (Cambridge) in 1998.
His main research interest is in functional programming languages, their implementation, and their application. He has led a succession of research projects focused around the design and implementation of production-quality functional-language systems for both uniprocessors and parallel machines. He was a key contributor to the design of the now-standard functional language Haskell, and is the lead designer of the widely-used Glasgow Haskell Compiler (GHC). He has written two textbooks about the implementation of functional languages.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Steen Lehmann" id="D7668B77A184B6C7C12578B9005D0895" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/D7668B77A184B6C7C12578B9005D0895/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Jayway" title="">
			<biography>Steen is the CTO of Jayway in Denmark. After being a Java developer for a decade, working for international software companies, Steen has found himself doing mostly Ruby on Rails development lately, both web applications and RESTful backends for mobile apps.
</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Stephen Ball" id="A9818555573FB9FEC125792F002F1A12" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/A9818555573FB9FEC125792F002F1A12/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Embarcadero Technologies Europe Ltd" title="">
			<biography>Stephen Ball has been leading development teams for over a decade within the UK and across Europe working with a range of blue chip companies including Hilton, American Express, Fitness First, Virgin Active; Stephen is a Charted IT Professional and is now working with Embarcadero (the owners of Delphi and C++ Builder) as a product Evangelist and is regularly speaking across EMEA.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Steven 'Doc' List" id="F0EDAADBD99BBC4AC1257880001E2AAB" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/F0EDAADBD99BBC4AC1257880001E2AAB/$file/thumb.jpg" company="ThoughtWorks" title="">
			<biography>Steven List (generally known as “Doc”) is currently a principal consultant with ThoughtWorks, with a career in software technology spanning three decades. Doc's long-term focus is on the core skills and strategies of management, leadership, team-building, and individual growth, and is an experienced presenter and public speaker, business and agile coach, trainer and workshop leader, and Open Space facilitator.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Svante Lidman" id="BFA7D277249CA4FDC125792800415AF7" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/BFA7D277249CA4FDC125792800415AF7/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Ivar Jacobson Intl. AB" title="">
			<biography>Svante has deep experience of building high performance software development teams delivering the results that the business needs and has more than 25 years experience in software development. He has held positions as development manager, program manager, project leader, consultant and trainer. In his current role he is coaching customers around the world to boost the results from their software development investments. Since 2000 Svante has worked for Ivar Jacobson Intl and Jaczone (acquired). Prior to that Svante has held management positions in software development at Microsoft, Rational Software, and Objectory and other companies.
Svante has a Master of Science degree in Engineering Physics from the Royal Institute of Technology in Stockholm.
</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Teresa Axner" id="F45A29D023E1E908C1257893002FFA08" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/F45A29D023E1E908C1257893002FFA08/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Self employed" title="">
			<biography>Teresa Axner co-founded the international Geek Women Unite!-network and is one of the chief architects behind the Scandinavian geek feminism movement. Originally a playwright and director, she now works as a writer, radio journalist and designer of educational games among other things. Teresa's main field of interest is the intersection between geek culture and social activism. Her heroes are Diana Wynne Jones, Simone de Beauvoir and Giles from Buffy the Vampire Slayer.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Tess Ferrandez" id="9C39C7E00442C884C125791F0030A8C5" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/9C39C7E00442C884C125791F0030A8C5/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Microsoft" title="">
			<biography>Tess is a developer evangelist at Microsoft and her job is to inspire developers and help them use the Microsoft products to their full potential. Right now the focus is on Windows Phone, Kinect, HTML5 and web apps, and she has a long history as a ASP.net developer and debugger. She runs a popular blog about debugging and development at http://blogs.msdn.com/Tess and you can reach her through the twitter handle @tessferrandez.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Thushara Wijewardena" id="B1553263EFB0373BC12578CA0027B62E" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/B1553263EFB0373BC12578CA0027B62E/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Exilesoft Pvt Ltd" title="">
			<biography>Thushara has been leading geographically distributed software teams over 12 years. During that time she has employed a variety of traditional and Agile processes. As the Project Director of Exilesoft, Thushara enjoys her day-to-day work with a large pool of technical specialists and a diversified clientele/integrated teams distributed in Norway, Australia and Sweden.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Tim Anglade" id="8CD19806A35933E4C12578B0005DF785" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/8CD19806A35933E4C12578B0005DF785/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Cloudant" title="">
			<biography>Tim is a snarky hipster who was into NOSQL before it was cool. In a previous life, he was a freelance consultant in Paris, a data scientist at the University of Maryland and a project manager for the NASAQ Stock Exchange. He’s currently working for a Data Hosting Analytics company called Cloudant. In his spare time, he organizes a worldwide network of user groups called the NOSQL Summer and maintains an archive of conversations about database technologies use-cases, called the NOSQL Tapes.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Tim Huckaby" id="2307AEA4865142ABC1257926003E6548" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/2307AEA4865142ABC1257926003E6548/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Microsoft" title="">
			<biography>Tim Huckaby is focused on the Natural User Interface (NUI)- Touch, Gesture, and Neural in Rich Client Technologies like HTML5, Silverlight, WPF, IOS on a broad spectrum of devices that include computers, tablets, the Surface, the Kinect, and mobile devices. 

Tim has been called a “Pioneer of the Smart Client Revolution” by the press. Tim has been awarded many times for the highest rated technical presentations and keynotes for Microsoft and many other technology conferences around the world. Tim is consistently rated in the top 10% of all speakers at these events. Tim has been on stage with, and done numerous keynote demos for many Microsoft executives including Bill Gates and Steve Ballmer. 

Tim founded InterKnowlogy, experts in .NET and Microsoft Platforms in 1999 and Actus Interactive Software in 2011 and has over 30 years of experience including serving on a Microsoft product team as a development lead on an architecture team on a Server Product. Tim is a Microsoft Regional Director, a Microsoft MVP and serves on many Microsoft councils and boards like the Microsoft .NET Partner Advisory Council. 
</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Tobias Fors" id="E3DE6B2E48E87028C125788000532C11" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/E3DE6B2E48E87028C125788000532C11/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Citerus" title="">
			<biography>Tobias Fors is a software management consultant, specialized in helping teams and organizations be more effective, ship software, and have fun together. He has helped numerous well-known Swedish companies improve the way they do software development.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Tobias Järlund" id="7524E50E541CCD89C12578AE00236B4C" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/7524E50E541CCD89C12578AE00236B4C/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Aftonbladet" title="">
			<biography>Tobias spent several years developing software for the academic world before he left to search happiness in the media industry. Today he works as Lead developer at Aftonbladet.se, the primary news source of the Swedish people. Tobias tries to master and be involved in all aspects of software development, with a passion for web performance, scalability and security.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Trevor Burnham" id="DD231B5D8CFED92BC125789F0059BDC0" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/DD231B5D8CFED92BC125789F0059BDC0/$file/thumb.jpg" company="DataBraid" title="">
			<biography>Trevor Burnham is a full-stack web developer with a passion for new technologies. He is the founder of DataBraid, a startup developing data analysis and visualization tools that support remote collaboration. When on Twitter, he goes by @TrevorBurnham and @CoffeeScript. When offline, he’s usually in Cambridge, MA.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Troels Møller" id="713C2309B5FA4CFAC12578A00049632B" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/713C2309B5FA4CFAC12578A00049632B/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Bitbureauet" title="">
			<biography>Troels Møller is an internet activist, with special interests in
copyright, censorship, data retention and logging etc. Spokesperson
for pro filesharing group Piratgruppen and co-founder of the internet
thinktank Bitbureauet. Studying masters degree in sociology and law at
Copenhagen University.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Troels Thomsen" id="F1B68C41BED92867C12578BF005DC4A2" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/F1B68C41BED92867C12578BF005DC4A2/$file/thumb.jpg" company="AppHarbor" title="">
			<biography>Troels has been programming since he was eleven and asked his father for an advice on how to kill time, so even though he dropped out of Computer Science from the University of Copenhagen a year early, he immediately pursued senior engineering and architect roles in Danish startups. He is now involved as a co-founder and technical lead in AppHarbor, a .NET Platform-as-a-Service.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Udi Dahan" id="647275791EA01DF3C125787F0069598A" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/647275791EA01DF3C125787F0069598A/$file/thumb.jpg" company="" title="">
			<biography>Mr. Udi Dahan is an internationally renowned expert on software architecture and design. Recognized with the coveted &quot;Most Valuable Professional&quot; award by Microsoft Corporation for solutions architecture and connected systems 4 years in a row, Mr. Dahan is also on the advisory board of Microsoft's next generation technology platforms: WCF/WF/OSLO, the Software Factories Initiative, and the Composite Application Library Guidance. He provides clients all over the world with training, mentoring and high-end architecture consulting services, specializing in Service-Oriented, scalable and secure enterprise architecture and design. Mr. Dahan is one of 33 experts in Europe recognized by the International .NET Association (INETA), an author and trainer for the International Association of Software Architects on Reliability, Availability, and Scalability, and an SOA, Web Services, and XML Guru recommended by Dr. Dobb's - the world's largest software magazine. Udi Dahan has a proven track record of solution design in Israel's largest companies in the fields of Defense, Travel, and Retail. From web projects in small internet startups, including government projects that push the limits of technology, to enterprise-scale programs with hundreds of developers and testers costing tens of millions of dollars - companies in all verticals and of all sizes entrust Mr. Dahan with providing them relevant and reliable architecture and design for their current and future requirements.
</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Will Jennings" id="3DF1D48DE8680ABBC125790D00261584" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/3DF1D48DE8680ABBC125790D00261584/$file/thumb.jpg" company="Whistle Works Media" title="">
			<biography>Will is a young animator and film maker living in Malmo, Sweden. He specialises in creating LEGO stop motion animations, and live action mini feature films. From a very early age, his passion, and inspiration for animating and movie making was fuelled by the work of; Nick Park (Wallace and Gromit), Gerry Anderson (Thunderbirds), and George Lucas (Star Wars). In 2008, Will became the youngest member of LEGO’s global ambassador program. Will is a student at Bladin’s International School in Malmo.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="William Van Hecke" id="4FDA3AC0B8F1F4F6C12578B9005DCB11" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/4FDA3AC0B8F1F4F6C12578B9005DCB11/$file/thumb.jpg" company="The Omni Group" title="">
			<biography>Bill is User Experience Lead at the Omni Group, one of the world’s most accomplished and affable Mac and iOS developers. His is the nebulous job of making software civilized enough to bring out in public. This involves lots of squinting six inches away from the Cinema Display at 3200% zoom and consulting etymology dictionaries to properly label buttons. It often ends up entwined with documentation, marketing, quality assurance, customer support, and Dungeon Mastering too.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Yehuda Katz" id="E10871750E5CA64BC12578AD006BF621" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/E10871750E5CA64BC12578AD006BF621/$file/thumb.jpg" company="" title="">
			<biography>Yehuda Katz is a member of the SproutCore, Ruby on Rails and jQuery Core Teams. Daytime, he works as an architect at Strobe. Yehuda is the co-author of the best-selling jQuery in Action, the upcoming Rails 3 in Action, and is a contributor to Ruby in Practice. He spends most of his time hacking on open source or traveling the world doing evangelism work. He blogs at http://yehudakatz.com and can be found on Twitter as @wycats.</biography>
		</speaker>
		<speaker name="Zeger Van Hese" id="88FF9BB4674FE7A8C125787F007680B4" photoFile="http://oredev.org/prod/oredev/2011program.nsf/0/88FF9BB4674FE7A8C125787F007680B4/$file/thumb.jpg" company="CTG" title="">
			<biography>Zeger started his professional career in the movie distribution business, only to discover that there are more bugs to be found in software testing. He has a passion for exploratory testing, testing in agile projects and, above all, continuous learning from different perspectives.</biography>
		</speaker>
	</speakers>
</program>
